<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

	<!-- generator="WordPress/5.9-alpha-51582" created="2021-08-09 20:50" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>WordPress News</title>
	<link>https://wordpress.org/news</link>
	<description>WordPress News</description>
	<pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 20:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://wordpress.org/</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://wordpress.org/news</wp:base_blog_url>

		<wp:author><wp:author_id>10573955</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[chanthaboune]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[chanthaboune@example.org]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Josepha]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Josepha]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>17810800</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[cbringmann@example.org]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Chloe Bringmann]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Chloe]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Bringmann]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>227158</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[eidolonnight]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[eidolonnight@example.org]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Nicholas Garofalo]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Nicholas]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Garofalo]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9-alpha-51582</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">14607090</site>
		<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 1: Welcome to your WP Briefing]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/02/welcome-to-your-wp-briefing/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[chanthaboune]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=9580</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Why this podcast now?</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There's a lot that goes into WordPress, and for anyone who isn't involved full time (and sometimes even for those who are), it can be tough to see it all. There is more to WordPress's success than the code within it or the open source freedoms behind it. To really understand what makes WordPress so unique, you would have to spend countless hours digging into its philosophy, the community that supports it, and the many years of learning that the software benefits from.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This podcast is for WordPress users, builders, and contributors of all levels. It's designed to give you quick insights into the longstanding philosophies of the WordPress open source project. Each episode will include:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>An easy-to-digest overview of a cool WP philosophy</li><li>A highlight of a community success story or a noteworthy contributor</li><li>A small list of big things to know about (or do) in the coming weeks</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And sometimes, when I just can't do a topic justice, I'll have a guest with me to talk through it together.<br></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/">Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/">Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/">Marcus Kazmierczak</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Show Notes</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>State of the Word and three trends in action</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:embed {"url":"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=QI3qCoiuG3w\u0026amp;t=17s","type":"video","providerNameSlug":"youtube","responsive":true,"className":"wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QI3qCoiuG3w&amp;t=17s
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:embed -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>What to look out for in 2021</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Goals: <a href="https://make.wordpress.org/updates/2021/01/21/big-picture-goals-2021/">https://make.wordpress.org/updates/2021/01/21/big-picture-goals-2021/</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>Community Highlight</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:embed {"url":"https:\/\/twitter.com\/daveloodts\/status\/1339495489834803200","type":"rich","providerNameSlug":"twitter","responsive":true} -->
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://twitter.com/daveloodts/status/1339495489834803200
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:embed -->

<!-- wp:heading {"level":3} -->
<h3>How to get involved&nbsp;</h3>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Get started helping with testing at: <a href="http://make.wordpress.org/test">make.wordpress.org/test</a></li><li>Learn more about Full Site Editing (FSE) at <a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/tag/core-editor/">core editor meetings</a></li><li>Find or Submit Workshops and Lesson Plans at: <a href="http://learn.wordpress.org">learn.wordpress.org</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more {"customText":"Click for transcript"} -->
<!--more Click for transcript-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Before we get going, let's talk a little bit about the purpose of this podcast. There is a lot that goes into WordPress. And for anyone who isn't involved full time, it can be really hard to see. And even when you are really involved, sometimes you just aren't trying to figure out any of the philosophical things that make WordPress unique. So you can think of this as a sort of WordPress appreciation for any level—and honestly, all levels of WordPress awareness. Bite-sized insights into what makes it all work.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So at the end of 2020, the project saw its first-ever virtual state of the word. There were many things in it that we look forward to seeing every year: we got a reminder of our roadmap and checked in on progress on things to date. And there was also a review of the releases that were shipped over the year.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This state of the word also included a few beautiful gems that you might miss if you don't have all the context. Matt mentioned three trends in action. I want to share the context for those because without the context, you don't really understand why they're so important for the WordPress project in general, certainly important to share in that particular presentation. Those three things were content that connects, e-commerce that sustains, and skills that elevate; we'll take them one at a time.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So content that connects refers directly to the WordPress project’s mission of democratizing publishing. Now, if you haven't heard of democratizing publishing, it's the idea that it should not be difficult for you to put your site online or to have an online presence. And especially, you should not be left out of any 21st-century opportunities because you don't know how to code. Everyone has a story to tell, and every story has ears that need to hear it or eyes that need to read it depending on your medium. But in a time where social media is dire and doom scrolling is part of the daily routine, it's nice to have a place where you can confidently own your voice and perspective. And more importantly, when we build a community, when we bring people around ideas and concepts and our passions, we feel more connected to the world around us. And I think that that's always a good idea.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second one was e-commerce that sustains, this to my mind, refers to the scads of success stories that we hear at WordPress events all across the globe. People come to those events to learn how to run a business online or how to build a site that supports their business, regardless of whether it's online or not. But also, they come to build a network that supports their growth and success.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of my favorite experiences at Word Camps is when you meet a first-time attendee, and they are there because they are starting a new business. And they just heard about this thing called WordPress, and they want to learn how to use it better to be a successful entrepreneur. And when I see those same attendees year after year at my local word camp, going from “I'm here just to learn how to do this and use this tool,” to “I did this great thing using this tool. This is the business that I have, this is the work that I do that WordPress site enables that;” that is such a compelling thing. And that is why I get passionate about WordPress and certainly why I continue to help make sure that all of our contributors can show up and keep WordPress running.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The third trend that Matt mentioned was skills that elevate, and this one probably is actually my favorite. I know it sounded like the second one was my favorite, but this one probably is my actual favorite. It refers to all of those who have done the hard work to learn how to use this software, set up e-commerce sites, and build websites for other people.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>They have taken all of those skills that they learned while creating content for themselves or putting together e-commerce sites that sustained their businesses or other people's businesses. And they turned that into their career: they can create sites for others, they can design excellent things using all of the tools that WordPress provides to them, they can develop custom solutions, where in some cases, no one can tell that WordPress runs it. I think that's so fascinating to see how people graduate from “I am here because I'm trying to enable my passions with this tool,” all the way out to, “I would like to help enable other people's passions with this tool, I want to help enable other people's journey and success and changing of their life stories.”It gives me chills to think about it every time.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So those are the three trends in action that were mentioned in the State of the Word. Again, I feel like, without that context, it's hard to know why it was so important for everyone to know it. But now that you have it, I hope that it is helpful for you. And I hope that it gives you some interest in learning a bit more about what the WordPress project does.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now that we're in 2021, we're all spending some time trying to get an idea of what the New Year holds for us; getting a handle on goals, getting a handle on what we think we can do and not do, habits to make and break as we go. And so I've been thinking about some of the things that I'm particularly interested in for the WordPress project in 2021. And the things I'm most excited about. I think that the things that I'm most excited about actually have to do with our necessary pivot to online learning and online events. 2020 will be etched in our memories forever as the year that made us grow and change and grapple with how we bring people together and teach 21st-century skills.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And the work that's being done on learn.wordpress.org through the training team and the community team and docs - that whole collaborative effort over there is so exciting to me. The ability for us to meet current and future WordPress users where they are and where they have to be right now and engage in a new way of learning so that they can still have all of the skills required to create their web presence, without necessarily having to travel all the way to a Word Camp, and put their health at risk. Or even in normal times, when they have to travel to an event and pay for that with their actual money, they also have the opportunity cost for all of our entrepreneurs. And then the cost of just not having that time to dedicate to building your business. I'm excited about that training and learning and educational opportunity that we're making available to more and more people in our community and elsewhere as we work our way through 2021.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So congratulations, you've made it through the biggest part of this podcast. This podcast, the WordPress Briefing, will always be pretty short and to the point. The first part will always have some really big questions, some good solid concepts to dig into about what makes WordPress run. I hope that I always make it easy to understand.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But also, if you have any questions, I hope that you take the time to follow-up because I want to hear from you! And I want to make sure that you have a concept of how we're getting things done.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For the last part here, we're going to have a community highlight, which will either be a contributor who has done some excellent work stewarding the WordPress project forward or a community submitted success story. Today, we have a success story that was sent to me via Twitter from Dave Lootz. He says: “15 years ago, I blindly decided to become a freelance web designer without any tech knowledge. Right now, I create awesome custom sites and shops, and I'm on a level where I have the freedom to choose my customers, my hours, my destiny, and that is the real power of WordPress.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now it's time for our small list of big things. I have three things for you today, all of which come right from a post that I'll share in the show notes with our big picture goals for the project for 2021.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The first one on there is Full Site Editing. We have a whole meeting dedicated to keeping the new block editor's work moving forward, and we can always use your help there. If you are not a developer or a designer, but you still want to help, there is an opportunity for testing the Full Site Editor as it becomes more and more available in the plugin. I will share links to both of those things in the show notes.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing that you can keep an eye on if you want to learn more about how we're doing things is learn.wordpress.org. I mentioned it earlier, and it is a new initiative that is in its early stages. It aims to bring training about WordPress and the 21st-century skills required to use WordPress to you no matter where you are.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The third thing on our small list of big things is some general contributor experience-type work we're doing this year. I am trying to help our contributors, especially when time and attention are at a premium. I'm trying to help support the tools that reclaim some of that manual effort that our contributors put in, that our volunteers worldwide have made available to us to make sure that WordPress succeeds in the long run. Ensuring that you all can continue to be happy and healthy and safe and contribute in the most meaningful way for you is high on my list all year every year. This year, we're going to try to take care of that with some automation in a few of our contributor teams.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So that, my friends, is your small list of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress Briefing. Again, I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in a couple of weeks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[For this inaugural podcast, Josepha will share a bit of what to expect from this podcast, some thoughts about the State of the Word 2020, and a list of focuses for the coming weeks.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>9580</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-02-01 16:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-02-01 16:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-16 22:22:32]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-16 22:22:32]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[welcome-to-your-wp-briefing]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_f8a4d14710a4adf4052ffbc3742e4c44]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">15 years ago i blindly decided to become a freelance webdesigner without any tech knowledge. Right now, i create awesome custom sites and shops. I&#39;m on a level where i have the freedom to choose my customers, my hours, my own destiny. That&#39;s the real power of WordPress.</p>&mdash; Dave Loodts (@daveloodts) <a href="https://twitter.com/daveloodts/status/1339495489834803200?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 17, 2020</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_f8a4d14710a4adf4052ffbc3742e4c44]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1626467955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17810800]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/01/wp-briefing-001.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12:26]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12mb]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12000488]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Announcing the WP Briefing - a new podcast where you can learn about where WordPress is going.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/01/wp-briefing-001.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 2: WordPress is Free(dom)]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/02/wordpress-is-freedom/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[chanthaboune]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=9722</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy gives quick explanations of the Four Freedoms of open source, the phrase “Free as in free speech, not free as in beer,” and why open source matters in the grand scheme of things.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Credits</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a href="https://www.gnu.org/philosophy/free-sw.en.html">Free software, defined</a></li><li><a href="https://hugh.blog/2019/03/15/becoming-a-good-open-source-citizen/">The analogy of cake according to Hugh Lashbrooke</a></li><li><a href="https://ma.tt/2014/01/four-freedoms/">Bonus content to Matt’s excellent viewpoint on The Four Freedoms</a></li><li><a href="https://twitter.com/topher1kenobe/status/1356698714996432897">Contributor Highlight</a></li><li><a href="https://wordpress.tv/event/wordcamp-india-2021/">WordCamp India videos</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/5-7/">WordPress 5.7</a> </li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/2021/02/03/committers-maintainers-and-emeriti/">Committers, Maintainers, and Emeriti</a></li><li>Keeping Up with Full Site Editing<ul><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/test/tag/fse-outreach-program/">https://make.wordpress.org/test/tag/fse-outreach-program/</a></li></ul></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:embed {"url":"https:\/\/make.wordpress.org\/core\/2020\/05\/20\/ways-to-keep-up-with-full-site-editing-fse\/","type":"wp-embed","providerNameSlug":"make-wordpress-core"} -->
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-wp-embed is-provider-make-wordpress-core wp-block-embed-make-wordpress-core"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
https://make.wordpress.org/core/2020/05/20/ways-to-keep-up-with-full-site-editing-fse/
</div></figure>
<!-- /wp:embed -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I'd like to start today with a look at the phrase “free as in free speech.” If you're familiar with the WordPress community, you might have heard it from another community member. And if you're not familiar with us, then this may be your first time hearing it. Either way, I think it's important for us to learn a bit more about it. The full phrase is “free as in speech, not free as in beer,” and specifically it relates to open source software. But WordPress happens to be a little bit of both of those things.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>WordPress is literally free, you can go right now to the download section of the WordPress website and own your own copy with the click of a button. There are some costs associated with getting your first site online. But for the software, zero, absolutely nothing. <strong>So it's free</strong>. But also WordPress is open source. And that's where the free as in free speech part comes in.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The four freedoms of open source as laid out in the early 90s are basically:</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list {"ordered":true} -->
<ol><li>the freedom to run the program for any purpose</li><li>the freedom to study how the program works, and change it so that it does your computing as you wish</li><li>the freedom to redistribute copies so that you can help your neighbor</li><li>the freedom to distribute copies of your modified versions giving the community a chance to benefit from your changes.</li></ol>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Sometime last year, or a couple of years ago, <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/hlashbrooke/">Hugh Lashbrooke</a>, who works in the WordPress community, did an excellent post about the Four Freedoms using cakes as an example. You will find a link in the show notes to that post because it's an excellent illustration. It was going to take too long for this. But I really think that if you're having a little bit of trouble hanging on to this concept of the four freedoms, then that's a great illustration.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It’s hard to know how these open source four freedoms matter on a daily basis. So from a practical standpoint, what this all means is that you can own a copy of the software that is easy to use, easy to study and learn from, easy to change, and easy to share. It also means that once you've shared your changes with others, those changes can also be brought back to the broader community so that they can also benefit from that change, which I am sure made the software a little bit better, just a little bit more functional. But from a philosophical standpoint, this means so much more.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The freedoms of open source, when applied at the scale of humanity, or even at the scale of 39% of the web, can enable the removal of barriers to opportunity in the world. You don't have to be rich to have an online presence. You don't have to find loopholes in proprietary platforms and hope that they never change their terms of service. You own all of the content that you create on a WordPress site and have the liberty to move it to a new host if you need to, or switch your theme if it fits your mood.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are compounding benefits to that. When it doesn't matter where you connect to the internet, or what Hard Knocks life has dealt you—when your location or language, or mobility can't prevent you from opening up a shop to sell your jam or your honey</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>or a site to promote your specific services—that opens up the opportunity for generational wealth that is really hard to tap into otherwise. And if you're not quite ready to come with me on that, then I think you might at least agree that having reliable passive income or an excellently trained lead generation funnel can offer stability in a time when the world is really unstable.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As always, if something in here doesn't make sense to you, or if you have a question you'd like to have answered, I want to hear from you. You can email me at wpbriefing@wordpress.org.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So there you have it. A really quick explanation of why open source matters to me on a day to day basis and why it might need to matter to you to a little bit; free as in free speech, but also a little bit free as in beer.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now it's time for our community highlight. I crowdsourced a few contributor success stories on&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Twitter. And I'm going to highlight them as this podcast progresses over the year. But before I do, I wanted to call out something that I thought was really remarkable.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I enjoyed seeing about a third of the people who came up as “this person was my buddy, my mentor as I was figuring out how to how to contribute to WordPress, and how WordPress as an ecosystem worked.” About a third of those people were women. And not only are they women, but they are women who were in WordPress leadership. And some of them are women who are currently in leadership in the project. And based on the list that, I'm seeing also women who probably will be in leadership in the future, both in WordPress and wherever else they happen to be doing that kind of support work. I think that's pretty amazing, because in technology, of course, there is a pretty understood lack of diversity in the voices that we see. I haven't checked recently, but for a long time, the number of women that we saw in the technology field was right about 10%. At some point, someone told me it was up to 14%.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The women that are showing up and being subject matter experts and being represented in WordPress are above and beyond that every single time. And we're not perfect. We have a lot of things that we have to do. And I for what I can make small, little changes in the systems that we have, about how we work in WordPress, how we work in the community, and how we work with each other. I asked my team reps to do the same thing. And so I think that, in the long run, what happens is we will have a more and more welcoming and open community and hopefully keep moving past that 30% of women that we're seeing and right on out into an excellent 50/50 split. But you know, that's probably a topic for some other podcasts.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I promised a community highlight from the crowdsourcing I did on Twitter. And the one that I want to highlight today is from <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/topher1kenobe/">Topher DeRosia</a>. He is one of the folks behind the <a href="https://heropress.com/">HeroPress</a> site, and he had this lovely story to tell.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>“When I was standing on the edge of the contributor pool. I asked <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/siobhan/">Siobhan McKeown</a> for help, and she quite kindly pushed me headfirst into #docs. Changed everything.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I love this story, not only because of the people involved but also it is so evocative. I know that when I started contributing to WordPress, I felt exactly the same way. A pool is exactly right.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And that brings us to our small list of big things. Our third segment of this show.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have four things on my list for you this week. The first is WordCamp India; they just wrapped up their first-ever online event, which ran over three subsequent weekends. So don't forget to check out wordpress.tv or our YouTube channel for some of those excellent sessions.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Item number two for you is that WordPress 5.7 is coming up on March 9. And I want to quickly clarify something there's been a bit of a misunderstanding and I think it's my fault. WordPress 5.7 will not include a Full Site Editing prototype in Core, that will still be in the Gutenberg plugin. But Item number three, Full Site Editing is coming to WordPress in 2021. And so you'll start seeing some updates and statuses and demos showing up. To help people get ready. Keep an eye on wordpress.org slash news, or follow your favorite committers on Twitter.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This leads me now to my fourth item on my small list of big things. I'm in the process of cleaning up our committer lists so that our new and learning contributors can easily tell who is active and can help them find their way into the project. So that my friends, is your small list of big things.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress briefing. I'm your host Josepha Haden Chomphosy. I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy gives quick explanations of the Four Freedoms of open source, the phrase “Free as in free speech, not free as in beer,” and why open source matters in the grand scheme of things. ]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>9722</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-02-15 16:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-02-15 16:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-16 22:23:05]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-16 22:23:05]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[wordpress-is-freedom]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_fc68a1a7a32d836dd478ebb946fad8fc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="PwXEg84dNG"><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/2020/05/20/ways-to-keep-up-with-full-site-editing-fse/">Ways to keep up with Full Site Editing (FSE)</a></blockquote><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" title="&#8220;Ways to keep up with Full Site Editing (FSE)&#8221; &#8212; Make WordPress Core" src="https://make.wordpress.org/core/2020/05/20/ways-to-keep-up-with-full-site-editing-fse/embed/#?secret=PwXEg84dNG" data-secret="PwXEg84dNG" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe>]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_time_fc68a1a7a32d836dd478ebb946fad8fc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1626474161]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_oembed_7cd260c4d97ca524aa0b6f3697a48ebc]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17810800]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/02/WP-Briefing-002.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10:17]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10mb]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/02/WP-Briefing-002.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9957921]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[WordPress is Free(dom)
In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy gives quick explanations of the Four Freedoms of open source, the phrase “Free as in free speech, not free as in beer,” and why open source matters in the grand scheme of things. ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 3: My Typical Day as WordPress’s Executive Director]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/03/my-typical-day-as-wordpresss-executive-director/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[chanthaboune]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=9825</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy speaks to her role as the Executive Director of WordPress. Learn about the day-to-day of her role and how it supports the mission of WordPress.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Credits</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/five-for-the-future/">Five for the Future</a></li><li><a href="https://twitter.com/arunaswp/status/1339344702466887686">Contributor Highlight&nbsp;</a></li><li><a href="http://make.wordpress.org/core">WordPress Core</a>&nbsp;</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I've been asked many times what the day-to-day work looks like for the Executive Director of the WordPress project. I don't really think I've done a great job of answering that question. My default answer is either too broad, and I say, “I helped turn the WordPress vision into reality by supporting the community of contributors,” or way too narrow, and I start telling people what's on my calendar. Probably no one cares about each entry on my calendar, and almost every contributor is covered by “I get things done by helping people.” So today, I invite you to join me in exploring the type of work required and the balance it takes to keep WordPress working.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>First, some context on the weekly activity I see in WordPress, on average, 1,800 to 2,000 contributors a week, participate in conversations and tickets across the entire WordPress project in our entire ecosystem. There are about 20 volunteer teams that are each led by two to three team reps. Each of those teams actually has smaller groups that work on specific things; all told, it's probably about 50 distinct teams. And probably quite a few more if you are very generous in your counting about what makes up a team for us.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Among those teams, a minimum of about 35 meetings a week are held, plus more for working groups. That doesn't take into account the things most people are aware of externally.&nbsp; It doesn't take into account the big quarterly or annual activity things like WordPress software releases or any of our events. When those sorts of things do happen, there's a bit of an increase in our activity.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;I work 40 to 60 hours a week on WordPress, depending on what's going on, to make sure that I know what's happening now; so that I have insight into what the next three to five years will bring. All of that is in support of <strong>the WordPress community, which I define as anyone who has ever interacted with WordPress ever</strong>, regardless of whether they know it or not. In case you're feeling a bit lost right now, we can shorthand that entire context as this is really big and really complex.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Given that giant scope, it makes sense that people wonder what the work looks like. So I'll talk about it in three big chunks: what I focus my time on, what I focus my attention on, and what helps me balance my decisions.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So first, what I focus my time on. I spend about a quarter of my time in meetings, mostly with current contributors, project leadership, and community members. I spend another quarter of my time in WordPress community outreach, checking in with current folks, reaching out to future WordPressers, and checking in with people that I haven't heard from in a long time to make sure that I know what they need and if there's anything that I can do to help. After that, I spend a bit under 15% of my time each on writing/communications work or ad hoc project work. I then spend 10% of my time reviewing proposals, editing, communication drafts for others, and determining my stances on discussions that we're having in tickets and elsewhere. I spend all of my remaining time planning for various goals, projects, initiatives and personally working to remove blockers for our volunteer contributors. So the bulk of my time, about 50% or more, is spent in calls with people, which makes sense if you've ever worked with me; personal connections with the community have been the best part of my job for a long time. Since the community is what makes WordPress so great, it's only natural that I want to stay connected.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second big chunk is what I focus my attention on. I pay attention to four big pillars of work in the project. The first one is the WordPress CMS itself. So that's the core team, accessibility, design, and many, many others. The second one is the WordPress community. And that's the training team, everybody who is working on the Learn initiative, and the actual community team as well.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The third big pillar that I focus on is the WordPress contributor experience, which is mostly the meta team but&nbsp; includes all of the teams they work with: plugins, themes, polyglots, etc. The fourth big pillar that I turn my attention to is our communication; what I am saying about the WordPress project to people outside of it and what I am helping our team reps to say about the work that we're accomplishing for the WordPress project inside the project. In general, we have to make sure that we coordinate a big group of contributors around a common idea or a common practice as we move forward.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Now, the way I focus both my time and attention probably isn't quite right if you're focused on a single feature or team. And it's definitely not right if you aren't spending 40 hours a week in the project; what that probably looks like for you is more like an hour in a team meeting, 30 minutes or so on clarifying conversations, and any remaining time that you are able to contribute focused on the feature that you're actually contributing to. And so, there you have it all my time and attention. That is WordPress in a nutshell.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This brings us to the third chunk, the balance part. You might be wondering, how do I make sure I am fair and balanced in decisions that I have to make. That is something that I think about all the time, and I take very seriously. It's hard to make decisions that might affect 2,000 people. It's even harder when those decisions might affect 40% of the web. I know that I don't have all the answers. And I'm fortunate enough to have 50 or 60 people in the community who offer me advice and guidance every single week. I'm in constant contact with the project lead, of course, but I also prioritize messages and concerns raised from team reps. And I always strive to understand before I try to problem solve. I don't always get it right, but I do always work to get better. And that is the day-to-day work of a WordPress executive director.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us to our community highlight. I tweeted out into the community asking for excellent examples of Freelancer success stories, and today I'm going to share a story from <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/ideag/">Arūnas Liuiza</a>. Their story goes like this:&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph {"align":"justify"} -->
<p class="has-text-align-justify">“For almost a decade, freelance WordPress gigs allowed me to support myself and my family and keep my full-time teaching position at the local college, which was paying peanuts but was an awesome, meaningful, and fulfilling. I am sincerely grateful for that.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us to our final segment of this brief podcast. The small list of big things to keep an eye out for in the next two weeks in WordPress. I only have two things this week. The first one is daylight saving time. It is that time of year where daylight saving time starts or stops at various parts in the globe. If you are a team rep here at WordPress, don't forget to talk to your teams in your meetings in the next few weeks to decide what you're going to do. You can move your team meeting if you want, and you can keep it where it is and see what new voices show up when it moves around for various people. Either way, make sure that you chat it out with your team and make sure that everybody understands what is and isn't moving on your calendar. That will also be relevant to any of our brand new work-from-home folks in the middle of this global pandemic.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing to share is that there is a major release of WordPress coming up that's going to happen on March 9th. It’s WordPress 5.7; it's going to be a good release. We've been working on it since December or maybe a little bit earlier. So keep an eye out for announcements about that here on wordpress.org/news, or if you want to follow more about the developer details and the process details you can head on over to wordpress.org/core. That, my friends, is your small list of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress briefing. I’m your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy speaks to her role as the Executive Director of WordPress. Learn about the day-to-day of her role and how it supports the mission of WordPress.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>9825</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-03-01 04:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-03-01 04:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:07:43]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:07:43]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[my-typical-day-as-wordpresss-executive-director]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/02/WP-Briefing-003.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9:33]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9.8mb]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/02/WP-Briefing-003.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9771930]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy speaks to her role as the Executive Director of WordPress. Learn about the day-to-day of her role and how it supports the mission of WordPress.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-03-26]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 4: How WordPress Improves]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/03/how-wordpress-improves/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 15:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[chanthaboune]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=9980</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/chanthaboune/">Josepha Haden Chomphosy</a> explores the WordPress release process. Tune in and learn the phases of a release and catch this week’s small list of big things.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Credits</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2021/03/esperanza/">WordPress 5.7 “Esperanza” </a></li><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Esperanza_Spalding">Esperanza Spalding</a></li><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2021/02/gutenberg-tutorial-reusable-blocks/">Gutenberg Tutorial: Reusable Blocks</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/test/">make.wordpress.org/test</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/handbook/contribute/git/">GitHub repository </a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>All right, so last week, we wrapped up and shipped the WordPress 5.7 release. The release team this time around was smaller than we've had in the last couple of years. By the numbers, it looks really good: 66 enhancements or feature requests went in, 127 bugs were fixed, and seven versions of a Gutenberg plugin were merged and backported. If you use WordPress, you are probably aware that we have new releases throughout the year, but you probably don't know much about the release process. There's not really a reason to know unless you're actively contributing to a release. For those interested in knowing more about how we improve WordPress, this week's exploration is for you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We're gonna take a look at what goes into WordPress releases and just kind of zoom our way in from the highest level. At the highest level, there are three major WordPress releases a year, plus the minor releases, plus Gutenberg releases. So if you're following current WordPress work and future WordPress work, that's going to get you to probably around <strong>30 releases a year</strong>. If we zoom in one level to the release itself, a single release of WordPress takes four to five months from start to the day that we ship, and an additional four to six weeks on support and translations, and minor releases after that. If you're looking from my vantage point, you'll see that WordPress releases have essentially five parts, some of which happen kind of simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The first part is planning and includes the project lead, lead developers, design; groups like that. The second phase is the creation phase when we're actually building the things that have to go into the CMS that involves the design, core, editor, mobile, and other teams. Then there's this phase that I like to refer to as the distribution phase. This is mostly done by the teams that make sure that WordPress is widely distributable; the polyglots team work on translations, accessibility does some work, docs make sure that everything is documented, and training, of course, gets things ready for when we have to be able to tell people how to use the release.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Then there is the fourth phase; I really don't think they go sequentially or in a waterfall format. The fourth-ish phase that I include, and that I tend to see, is this extending and iteration phase. It's the phase where we see our theme authors and our plugin authors, folks who are doing support, show up and help us to make sure that WordPress is available not only widely but broadly to ensure that their audiences as theme authors and plugin authors are covered in the features that they need based on what they are using WordPress for. The fifth phase is the part of our communication that involves the community team, especially marketing, WordPressTV, and learn.wordpress.org. Basically, anyone who's showing up to make sure that we all share what happened in the release, the features that are coming, and how that affects the users is involved in that particular phase. So five big phases of what happens over those four to five months, and then for the month or month and a half afterward.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If we zoom in a bit more on the creation phase, each release has people who lead the work and coordinate contributor efforts during the course of the release. For any given release, hundreds of people contribute and receive credit for moving the WordPress project forward. Okay, hold on a second. Let's pump the brakes and zoom in a bit on that. Hundreds of people work on every major release for a project that powers over 40% of the web that feels like a small number. But for the people who process the contributions in preparation for release, it's actually pretty substantial. For every release, there is a small team of leaders who asked the hard questions. Is this a usable feature? Does this make WordPress better overall? And, of course, is this ready to ship?&nbsp; Some of those leaders, a smaller subset of even the leaders that we have already, are committers who actually prep and merge patches to the CMS; they don't do all the work to create a design or write all the code. This tiny group of people processes hundreds and hundreds of bug fixes, improvements, and enhancements that have been submitted over the course of months and sometimes years. As a side note, that whole process is a little smaller, a little faster in the Gutenberg featured plugin, but the basic parts are still there. Alright, so we've zoomed from the big picture way into some of the finer details, and it really looks like any other project cycle. So now, I'm going to layer in the filter of open source to that process.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are a couple of things that make building software in an open source environment so different. The first is that the code is readily available. If you have a basic understanding of the languages, you can see the code, learn from it, and make suggestions about improving it. Second, you consider the user a co-developer in the process, which means that as long as people use your product, they will have opinions on what you shipped. This way of iterating improves WordPress and ties back to one of my favorite open source principles. The idea that with many eyes, all bugs are shallow. To me, that means that with enough people looking at a problem, someone is bound to be able to see the solution.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This brings us to our community highlight, the segment where I share a note about contributors who have helped others along the way or a WordPress success story. This week's highlight is from Nok in our Bangkok community. When asked to help her find her way into the WordPress community, she said, “@shinichiN who started the WordPress community in Bangkok and encouraged me to contribute, and also @mayukojpn has introduced me to the WP community team to join as a deputy. “ Thank you for sharing those two inspiring people with us. And if you, listener, have any stories that you would like to share of your own WordPress success or people that you have been so grateful to help you find your way in the project, you can feel free to email those to me at <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us to our final segment of the WP Briefing, the small list of big things. I only have three things to share with you this week. The first one is that about a week ago, we had our first release of 2021. It was the WordPress 5.7 release, titled Esperanza. If you have not yet seen it, go ahead and update your website or check with your host and make sure that they have updated you if you're on a managed host. And then take a listen to the artists that it's named after.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing that I want you to keep an eye out for is wordpress.org/news. We are starting a new series of content that gets at the heart of some of Gutenberg’s basic parts; there’s a lot of change coming up in the next few releases of WordPress. And the most important thing to me is that you understand what we're trying to change and where those changes are primarily taking place. There will be a couple of tutorials that go up there over the course of the of the next few weeks. The third item on the small list of big things is to remind you of our call for testing. As I mentioned earlier in the podcast, the users of any open source software are the code developers; the software built is supposed to make your life and work easier. When you test things and find interactions that can use a little bit of refinement or features that are not working exactly as expected, it's incredibly helpful for us to have that information to always make sure that we're solving problems instead of accidentally creating them. If you want to participate in the Current call for testing, you can head over to make.wordpress.org/test. Or, if you've been doing your own testing, you can also submit any bugs you have found in the GitHub repo, which I will share in the show notes below. So that, my friends, is your small list of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress briefing. I’m your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy explores the WordPress release process. Tune in to learn about what goes into a release and catch this week’s small list of big things.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>9980</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-03-15 15:08:47]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-03-15 15:08:47]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:07:53]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:07:53]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how-wordpress-improves]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/03/WP-Briefing-004.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10:52]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/03/WP-Briefing-004.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-03-12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10494999]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 5: Talking Full Site Editing with Matías Ventura]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/03/talking-full-site-editing-with-matias-ventura/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10013</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha is joined by Matías Ventura, also known as “the spark behind the vision of Gutenberg.” Josepha and Matías discuss full site editing and answer your questions, from “is full site editing a standalone plugin?” to “will full site editing break my current site?”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Credits</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/themes/tt1-blocks/">Twenty Twenty One theme</a></li><li><a href="https://centroamerica.wordcamp.org/2021/">Word Camp Central America </a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/2021/03/12/q2-listening-hours-april-7th-2021/">2021 Second Quarter Listening Hours with Matt Mullenweg and Josepha Haden Chomphosy</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [0:41]: This month, we have a bonus briefing, so I've asked my dear friend and colleague <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/matveb/">Matías Ventura</a> to join me. Matías was recently called “the spark behind the vision of Gutenberg.” With full site editing coming our way in 202, I asked if he would join me for a quick Q&amp;A. Welcome, Matías.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [0:56]: Hello, hello! Thanks for inviting me. It's a pleasure to be here.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [1:00]: Well, I'm delighted to have you. And I think that we have a lot of excellent questions. All right, so Matías, we actually ended up with questions in about three different groupings. And so I'm going to start with the “what is it about full site editing,” sorts of questions that people had. We're gonna work our way into “what are we doing with it?” and then “how are we planning on getting this out the door?” Then, a couple of big picture questions that people asked. We're just gonna leap right in this full site editing part of the Gutenberg plugin, or is it a standalone plugin?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [1:39]: Okay, we'll start with the basics. Full site editing is part of the Gutenberg plugin right now. I think it's important to mention that full site editing is like an umbrella for several projects that we're working on. They are all aiming to bring blocks into more parts of your site so that editing becomes easier and more expressive, and so on. So full site editing right now encompasses adding a ton of new blocks. I think we have around 20 new blocks coming in, including navigation query, site, title, logo, etc. There's also the interface to interact with templates outside of the content; that's another big part of the full site editing project. We also have a lot of new design tools included, many of these have been released in previous major releases, but they still comprise a strong part of what full site editing is. We also have something called Global Styles, which aims to allow people to configure the visual aspects of blogs across the entire site, not just on any individual blog. And of course, then there's a whole layer of how we utilize these tools. It can get complex because there are many layers and projects that need to come together. So yeah, all of these are accessible through the Gutenberg plugin right now.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [3:07]: Yeah. So it's not a standalone plugin. If you wanted to check out full site editing the site editor experience as it is now, you would just have to make sure you had the Gutenberg plugin on your site. Right?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías: Yes, correct.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha:&nbsp; So a couple of the questions related to this are how exactly do I enable it on my site? And what is the easiest and safest way to try this on my site? And I think the answer is, is right in there. It's in the Gutenberg plugin. And so if you have that plugin, you don't need the testing plugin or anything else to make that work, right?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [3:51]:&nbsp; No, you like, you might need to install a theme like Twenty Twenty One blocks that unlock some of these new interfaces that we just talked about. Like other of these pieces are available for anything. But some of these, like the interface to edit templates, right now only talk with things that know how to express their desire.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [4:14]: And I think we have less than 10 themes right now that do that, but I'll leave some links to at least 2021 blocks in the show notes. And then, if there are another one or two themes that I can find, I can add those in there as well.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So you have to have the Gutenberg plugin; you have to have a theme that works with that site editor kind of experience. And then you're safe to try everything out. It shows up in your left toolbar just like any other thing, like if you were working with plugins, or if you were adding a post or anything else, right?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [4:51]: Yes, correct. And so, some of these details are being worked on right now. Like how and where you access things, and so on. These things are subject to change, but right now, you have this site editor beta in the sidebar when both you have the plugin running and a theme that's capable.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [5:10]: Yeah. Excellent note. If you are running this on a production website, I would recommend you not do that unless you are very, very good with WordPress. It's a really safe and easy thing to test and try out. But because it is still in beta, I recommend always putting it on a test site. I have a couple of different test sites that I run on myself. Another question that I had was, “will full site editing slow down my site?” And I think we have some refreshed performance tests coming out about that. And maybe they'll be out by the time we publish this podcast.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [5:49]: Yeah, I mean, like the performance has been one of the major focuses for the whole project. In many cases, it should speed up things because we're like, I think one of the big pieces that these projects bring into the picture, especially for themes, is that it allows only the necessary assets to be loaded on the front end. For example, if for a given page, there are, I don't know, 10-15 blocks being used, you would only get the CSS and scrapes and so on related to those blocks. This can cut down on a lot a ton of CSS that themes used to end queue on a side, particularly if you were trying to customize many widgets and so on, like a lot of themes have the full styles or multiple widgets, even third party plugins, and so on. So one of the advantages of having this blog system is that we can know at the time of rendering what blogs are being used and only load those assets.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [6:50]: Excellent. Another big question that we have is, “does full site editing work with the classic editor? And does it work with other builders?” I think that's a really big answer if you're going to get super deep into it. But I think that the short answer is yes, it does. Is that fair?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [7:08]: Yeah, I don't think it touches a bit on that full site editing is not like a single thing. There are multiple projects around it. So again, like the template editor that only deals with blogs, it doesn't have a lot to do with a classic editor. But the classic editor use for both doesn't change anything at all; like the same way that when the block editor was introduced, it didn't change how you could still write posts in the classic editor. You will still be able to do that.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [7:41]: And if you are brand new to WordPress person, or, I mean, I guess at this point, you don't have to be super brand new. If you're fairly new to WordPress person and have no idea what we're talking about when we say the classic editor, you don't really have to worry about it either. You don't have to go and find out what that is; the block editor that you have right now works perfectly for what you're trying to do. So if you don't know what I mean when I say classic editor, don't worry about chasing it down either.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I think that this last question we accidentally answered earlier, but I'm going to go ahead and ask it anyway since I received it. “I keep hearing that you can use the site editor with the 2021 theme. But I don't seem to be able to. What am I missing?” I think the answer is that there's the Twenty Twenty One theme shipped with the WordPress release 5.6. And then there is the Twenty Twenty One blocks theme; those are two different themes. The link to the Twenty Twenty One block theme is going to be in our show notes this time around. And so, if you have been trying to use the full site editor with Twenty Twenty One and not succeeding, try the link to the one below. And I bet that that will work for you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [8:50]: Yes, that's correct.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [8:51]: All right, excellent. Well, that brings us kind of into our second set of questions, which is about how we are doing it. The first one that folks have is “will full site editing be on by default in the next release. In this context, the next release is WordPress 5.8. But I think it's a safe question to ask if full site editing will be on by default in the release that it's planned for.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [9:15]: Yeah, and for this, I need to go back to the same principle of many projects because there are many pieces of full site editing, and we have been merging them in major releases, particularly like the blocks and the design tools. There are more coming in that we want to make accessible as soon as possible. The full experience that requires a theme to opt-in to templates using blogs won’t be by default; it requires a specific theme running. A lot of these details we're still like determining exactly what projects are ready to be merged and so on. But yeah, if you have a theme right now that works the way you want, it doesn't change anything there. If anything, it adds some more capabilities and more customization tools, and so on. And the theme can also regulate how much they want to incorporate.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [10:13]: Matías, you've mentioned a couple of times in this podcast so far like this is a really complex and really complicated part of this work. And just for anyone out there who's either encountering Gutenberg or full site editing or this podcast for the first time, I think a tiny bit of context that's worth having here is that Matías and I have been working on this together in various capacities for like, five years. And Matías has probably been working on this for practically a decade. So, when we say that this is a really complicated problem, and when we say that this is a complex set of issues that we're working with like, it is all that we have been thinking about for I want to say at least the last three or four years, but certainly it's all that we have been trying to untangle for quite a bit of time before that as well. So we don't take it lightly when we're like, “this is complicated;” we mean it. It's really complicated. And we're trying our hardest over here as WordPress.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The next big question, since we're all stuck in the “it's very complicated,” part of things is the question, “will this update break my current site?” Like, if I have a site that is updated and ready, and it's exactly as I wanted it to be, and it took me two years to get there will full site editing, whichever release it's in. Currently, 5.8 is what we're planning for. Will that break anything on my site as I know it right now?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [11:44]: No, not at all. One of the major things that the WordPress team, the WordPress community, always cares so much about, never to break things. Many of these things are stepping stones that you can adopt, as we've talked about full site editing. But for example, we also have a few concurrent projects around the widget screen and the navigation screen that are meant to bring blocks into existing interfaces. So again, the theme doesn't need to change, and a lot of care is being put into making this more like you're unlocking new features, and nothing really breaks or falls apart.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [12:23]: This update, like all the other updates, should have minimal, minimal impact on what you have to actively fix on your site. Every once in a while, a bug is gonna get by. We can't say that we're 100% perfect with not breaking things. But also, we always and I and I know that we're planning on this for our remaining releases for the rest of the year. At the very least, I can't imagine we'd ever change it. But after every major release, we always make a plan to have a minor release within the next one or two weeks. Because we know that a broken thing on a site is really incredibly impactful, even if you're only 1% of the sites that had that happen to it. And so I think that's true in this case, too. And getting that feedback back from all of the people who are actually using WordPress is the thing that makes us be able to kind of move quickly when we do see those problems.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of the questions that we have been getting is, “can I see a live preview without saving the changes that I made?” When I got this question, I didn't actually understand it. And so I went and looked at a site without the Gutenberg plugin on it, and then a site with the Gutenberg plugin on it. And of course, on sites without Gutenberg, without the block editor, without full site editing, when you are looking to preview, you have the option to open up your preview in a new window. And you don't have that with Gutenberg because it's supposed to be a true WYSIWYG editor. A true what you see is what you get, editor. I think that the answer to this is, yes, you can see a live preview without actually saving the changes on the front end of your site. But you don't actually have to reload anything. You don't have to open it up in a new window. You don't have to, like, actively click “please show me a preview” because what you see in your editing screen should be what you see at the end of your app as an end-user.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [14:28]: Yeah, that's the sort of the main gist to it. Yes, the site editor is built so that it always reflects the front end as truly as possible, so that's one layer. Also, the preview tools should allow you to see in different devices like mobile breakpoints, and I don't know if they will have breakpoints and stuff like that. There are a lot of things in the current interface that is just not enabled. There are some challenges in the sidebar. Because the site editor is not just focused on a single post, it's focused on the entire site. So, there can be many, many changes that need to be shadowed for the site.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you're changing the site title, some of the global styles, aspects, and so on need to be orchestrated. So, to see in the previewing new window, there are some challenges there to integrate. Again, the interface is not final yet; a lot of these things are still being tweaked and improved. There are many things from the regular post editor that are not enabled yet. But they will be enabled. So yeah, it's a, I guess, it's not a simple thing to answer. Because, again, the idea of previewing the site that's core to the whole project is that you're always interacting in the same way that when you're in the customizer, you're seeing the preview all the time. That's the main scope of this project,</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [15:54]: Excellent. Changes like that changes to your workflow can be really hard to get your mind around, especially if part of that existing workflow was there to create some confidence in what you're seeing with your users. And so I understand. Now that I've researched that question a bit, I see where that's coming from. Based on existing workflows and existing patterns that we have for ourselves in WordPress, will we need to have a theme to use the full site editor?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [16:33]: I think we've already covered some of these. And again, they are tools that can work on any existing theme. There is other stuff that needs space-specific themes to opt-in into these tools, like blog templates and so on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [16:50]: Yes, I think the question that we have next, because I see that the literal next question I have is actually something we have covered; just because we're being pretty conversational about it, not because anyone already asked the question. So I'm actually going to skip to the last question of this section that I received. I got this next one via Twitter. The question is, “how do you view the role of themes once full site editing is fully rolled out and all the page elements (content, headers, widgets, footers, etc.) and all the views are managed via blocks and block patterns? Will things become typographic and block styles?”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [17:28]: I think this is a great question because it goes to the heart of, why are we doing all this. One of the main reasons is to empower users more. WordPress has been democratizing publishing for a while; this is another step into allowing themes to get more customization tools and more control over their site if they want to. I think the recent call for testing has focused on the 404 page, for example. That's something that forever has been locked away from users. And it's also something that, as a theme developer, and I used to develop themes a long time ago, that was one of the things where you decide what sort of approach you take for the 404 page. Maybe sometimes you want to have something more whimsical. Sometimes you need something more serious. And committing to one when you can have such a diverse and broad user base can be challenging. With these, it becomes as easy as offering a few different patterns for that template. Then the user will always be able to change the copy and modify something. So again, it opens up a lot of these things that used to be locked down. However, from a theme perspective, I think this doesn't reduce the theme at all. If anything, it allows the theme to focus less on coding and functions and more on design expression and aesthetics. I don't think that would ever be exhausted. That will always remain as diverse as humans are interacting with WordPress. And so it's not that I don't see it's just as like, typographic and block styles. How do you express a template, how do you express the structure, what choices you quote, what choices you make as a theme builder? And of course, there are many degrees of control there. Because a site maintainer may not want the 404 template to be editable, that sort of control will always be present.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [19:38]: Yeah. And really fast. I have to add a caveat to a thing that you said in there. For anyone who's listening keenly, you may have heard Matías say that the users can update any of the content there - any of the copy. In this context, we're talking about users as in the people who are maintaining the site, not people who are visiting your site. Visitors to your site will not be able to change any copy on your page unless you've done something very interesting with your WordPress site, which is also fine if that's what you prefer to do. By default, your visitors can't change everything on your website, which is good news, frankly.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So I've got one logistics question, which I'm happy to take. And then one is kind of a big picture question that I also got from Twitter. “What about the classic editor block; what is going to happen to that? And when will we know?” So ages and ages ago, before COVID? I think so. Probably maybe a couple of years ago, Matt said that the classic editor plugin would be supported through the end of 2021. And that is still the case; there will be active support on that through the end of 2021. After that, it will not be actively supported anymore. It won't be removed from any place that you can get access to right now. In a “this is the end of its lifecycle” sort of way, we just won't have anyone who is currently committed to maintaining that plugin anymore. So that's what's happening at the end of the year. And yeah, at the end of 2021. The big question that we have is, “why is full site editing being so rushed?” I think this is a bit of a loaded question.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [21:32]: Yeah, I think I think it's still a fair question, though. I think we're dealing with two things here. And one is ensuring that we release things in the best state possible. And also, some of the urgency is to offer tools that we know that people lack right now and that could really benefit from. Making that determination is very tricky. The full site editing project has been in the works for the last couple of years. If we count the initial phase of Gutenberg, that's four to five years. We've been doing many calls for testing, which I think have been super useful to catch issues and reflect as a community on where things are going; how do we integrate with these? How do we use it? What are the shortcomings? What do we need to do? Based on all of these, we'll continue to make decisions on when things become ready. We're not committed to releasing something that's not in a good state. And I think we will always be very careful about that. There are these two competing senses of the urgency - of getting some of these tools out, and because it also benefits from the feedback loops. I always say that, in many ways, the initial phase of Gutenberg, to me, is not finished. We took the initial two years to do the 5.0 release, the initial block editor, and so on. But, it's still being improved at a very fast pace, among all the recent major releases improvements to the editor were included; that will continue to be the case. In many ways, phase one is not finished. And the moment we choose to release some of these tools or editing tools, it won't be finished either. They will need to continue to grow, mature, and incorporate a lot of the feedback. Even the things that the ecosystem is building around. I've seen a few themes already that are incorporating a blank canvas template so that you can use them in some pages and take over and do everything with blocks. So even the community and ecosystem as a whole is also sort of paving the way for what needs to come.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [24:06]: I think from my perspective, and of course, I'm on the people side of things, the communication side of things, the logistics side of things; I have a frequently a very different view from what a lot of other folks are seeing. And so from my side of things, I have to say, I'm communicating about this change in a really broad way, which has not been happening since 2019 when we started the work. We've been communicating broadly with the WordPress community, but not with everybody who uses WordPress. So, I think that for a lot of people, this looks like a project that we started really actively working on in the last six months or so. And now we're just racing toward a finish line. I think that there's, there's not been a lot of awareness of everything that's gone into it. And so, on the one hand, it feels a little less rushed to me knowing the full length of the history on this. But also, as you said, I really think that this gets a bunch of tools to people who otherwise have not been able to accomplish these things in WordPress or otherwise. I am so anxious to get something to people who really can benefit from this change the most. And it's the nature of the open source, right that like, one, as long as you have users, you're going to have stuff you have to fix in your software. So we're never really, really going to be done with this; there's not going to be like a done point of WordPress. And the second thing is, I think it's generally true that you don't really start getting full user feedback until after you have launched your major release. I think that we see that a lot in open source software; you can bring in as many people as you think you can in your user tests heading up to it. And in your accessibility tests. And, in general, quality assurance tests. You can bring in a lot of people and still not have gotten the full understanding of the various niche use cases that your users will bring to you. Because at this point, we're like 40% of the web. And that means that we're serving this majority collection of increasingly minority voices and niche voices in the space. And so, a little bit I feel a sense of urgency; I feel a bit of anxiousness about trying to get this out there for one, to get the tools in the hands of the people who can benefit the most from them, but also so that we can start really getting the full stress test of this software out and get that feedback in so that we can really build something responsive to what our users need our long tail, “anyone who ever uses WordPress ever,” definition of users. And so, that's why I feel a sense of urgency around it. Even though you know, as I said, you and I have been working on this for like five years, and you've been working on it for a decade or something. I actually don't know how long it's been worked on.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [27:35]: Now that makes me feel a bit old.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [27:40]: Nobody makes Matías feel old. He is a lovely, wonderful colleague. Sorry, Matías, If I made you feel old.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [27:46]: No, that's totally fine. I also want to add that full site editing is not like a single toggle that's going to drop into a major release. So I think that's important to consider, I think this entire year is going to see a lot of these tools being, and sometimes the sort of the end-user is not the, again, the site maintainer. Still, you can also be the theme developer; I think there are many tools that would be empowering for theme developers to use. Again, we mentioned there are like five to ten themes, block themes right now. That needs to grow a lot, and that only grows through these sorts of feedback loops. And the theme community pushing things forward and seeing where things can lead to. I'm very excited about the pattern directory integration because I think that can also combine with blog themes in very powerful ways. Imagine if, I don't know many of these patterns that are very common on the web and very needed, that if we can refine them together with a second community and make them available across themes, you can combine a header from one theme with a content of another; all these sorts of mixtures could happen. All of this needs exploration, the creativity of the entire community, and so on. In that sense, getting all these tools, even if it doesn't immediately change anything for like the site itself, starts to unlock a lot of things.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [29:27]: I'm going to take a bit of your answer from there and tie it all the way back to your first answer that we had when you joined me today. And say, I think you're absolutely right. We have a set of users in our theme authors and our plugin developers as well that we desperately need to get looking at this set of tools. I hope that what we are shipping in the first iteration of this serves as an opportunity for all of those theme authors and agency owners, plugin authors, WordPress site configurers freelancers. Like, I really hope that this puts it into a really accessible, easy-to-access space for them so that they can do those experiments based on what they know their users need the most. They are the group that has the closest access to site maintainers. And what they need compared to, for instance, me or a potential you like we have a lot of information, you and I, we do a lot of tests, we have a strong sense of what is needed at the moment, but we don't have as a close connection that our theme and agency and plugin folks all have. And so that's another part of why I'm so excited to get this out in the current iteration of it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [31:04]: That was a lot of questions in a little bit of time. This is going to be officially my longest WordPress briefing. Matías, I am so glad that you were able to join me today. And I think that everyone's going to be really, really excited to hear your answers to these questions.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Matías [31:23]: Thank you for having me.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Josepha [31:25]: All right, my friends. That brings us into our small list of big things. I'm going to skip our community highlight today just because we had a slightly longer word press briefing in our bonus iteration today. But the small list of big things. The first thing is WordCamp Central America is coming up on April 15; there is a registration link in the show notes that you can access your tickets with. I recommend that you go; we've got a lot of excellent speakers coming up there and a lot of good content and good training and learning for y'all. The second thing is that Matt Mullenweg and I have listening hours coming up with the community in the first week of April. I'll add the link to register for those in the show notes as well; it's just a few minutes for you all to stop by, check-in, see what's going on, and share some celebrations or concerns with us. And I hope that I see you there.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So that my friends is your small list of big things. Thank you for joining in today for the WordPress briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha is joined by Matías Ventura, also known as “the spark behind the vision of Gutenberg." Josepha and Matías discuss full site editing and answer your questions, from “is full site editing a standalone plugin?” to “will full site editing break my current site?”
]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10013</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-03-29 15:05:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-03-29 15:05:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:02]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:02]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[talking-full-site-editing-with-matias-ventura]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="gutenberg"><![CDATA[Gutenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/03/WP-Briefing-005.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[33:04]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[31.8MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/03/WP-Briefing-005.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[31812171]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Talking Full Site Editing with Matías Ventura

]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 6: Who Is WordPress?]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/04/who-is-wordpress/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 14:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10099</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha explores the five groups within the WordPress ecosystem and provides a high-level example of how they interact and support one another. As always, stay tuned for the small list of big things and a contributor highlight.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Credits</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Get to know<a href="https://make.wordpress.org/"> WordPress Teams</a></li><li><a href="https://wordpress.tv/2017/12/10/josepha-haden-beginners-guide-to-contributions/">Five Steps of Volunteer Engagement </a></li><li><a href="https://twitter.com/CoachBirgit/status/1339516878495117313">Community Highlight </a></li><li><a href="https://centroamerica.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Centroamérica 2021 Online</a> (<a href="https://centroamerica.wordcamp.org/2021/sesiones/">Schedule</a>)</li><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2021/03/so-you-want-to-make-block-patterns/">So you want to make block patterns?</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1h73xMwjSRkJJsn7ooiwXFeZpd0hxXh26pJ7qXzI5iUg/edit#gid=0">Gutenberg Tutorial sign-up</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In the first episode of this podcast, I said that there's a lot that goes into WordPress, that's really hard to see. One of the hardest things to see about the WordPress project as you get started is the overall structure. There is quite a bit of documentation that can clarify the basics: the names of teams, what they work on, and where, and when they meet. The way that they influence and support each other can really feel like a bit of a mystery. So today, I'm going to break down the WordPress community into five big groups; I want you to keep a couple of things in mind.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Firstly, these are high-level and based on my observations. Each of these groups can be further broken down into subgroups. So while you may not feel represented in this exact five, you are included if you were to dig a little bit deeper. The second thing to keep in mind is that the makeup of these groups is pretty fluid. Many community members find themselves in more than one group, but generally not far off. Some group two folks end up in group three, depending on the situation, people in group four can also end up in group five, and so on. As with so many things that I share, I'm not trying to insist that one size fits all. I'm not trying to put the WordPress community into a box. This is just a basic framework to understand how it all fits together. Alright, are you ready? I'm ready. Let's do it!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Okay, I have a broad definition of the community, which I have mentioned before. I believe that the community is anyone who has interacted with WordPress, whether they know it or not. So, I'll start from way out there and work my way in that first group; we’re going to call our <strong>Visitors</strong>.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Visitors</strong> are people who arrive at a WordPress site to gain information or engage in an activity. Sometimes they know it's a WordPress site, but most of the time, they don't. The second group are <strong>Users</strong>, people who use WordPress as their CMS. So, that's website builders, website designers, small businesses, content creators, and the list goes on and on. The third group I like to refer to is the <strong>Extenders</strong>. Those are people who extend WordPress through the creation of blocks, themes, plugins, and more. There are also people who teach WordPress to others through WordPress podcasts, and newsletters and tutorials. The fourth group I refer to as our <strong>Contributors</strong> is the people who contribute to the open source software and the infrastructure supporting it, but not necessarily the same people who contribute directly to their own product. And then there's group five, <strong>Leaders</strong>. Those are people who help drive the vision and strategy for WordPress; the most notable member of that group is of course, Matt Mullenweg. And I'm also in that group.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Each of these groups directly influenced the groups on either side. For example, a WordPress user is affected by both visitors and extenders. Imagine a content creator who shares their passion for photography through a WordPress site; this photographer may have visitors that need to purchase photos. In response, the user now has a need to make it possible for visitors to purchase photos on a site. So they go to what we consider the extenders, people who have built a plugin that supports that need. And as a result, that user can install that on their site. And they have have satisfied the need of the visitors to their site, the people who now can purchase photos.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are a lot of examples like this in the WordPress project. Every small pattern that you see is mirrored in the larger patterns across our ecosystem. And every large pattern you see in the ecosystem can be seen among our teams. It's pretty cool to look at really. So, why should this matter to you? From a very practical standpoint, this matters for anyone who's trying to learn more about contributing to the WordPress project. These five groups mirror very closely the five steps of volunteer engagement that we see across the ecosystem and from a more philosophical standpoint, it's just kind of nice to know who your neighbors are. Without the influence and support of the groups around us, it can be hard to know whether we're on the right track or not. So take a look to your left and look to your right, and get to know your partners in this project.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us now to our community highlight, the segment where I share a note about contributors who have helped others along the way, or WordPress success story. This week's highlight is from @CoachBirgit, <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/coachbirgit/">Birgit Olzem</a>, a longtime contributor and a friend of mine. Her success story goes like this.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>WordPress has allowed me as a mother of five to leave a toxic marriage for good.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Later, the community picked me up when I became seriously ill.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So I can say from the bottom of my heart, that working with WordPress has saved my life.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And now our small list of big things. I've got three things for you this week. I think that they're all very important. And I hope you check them all out. The first one is a reminder that word camp Central America is coming up on April 15 and 16th. If you have not registered for tickets, you still have time, I will share a link to the registration page and the schedule in the show notes below.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing on our small list of big things is that the Gutenberg 10.4 release is coming out later this week on April 14th. It's an important release because it's when we take a look at the current iteration of full site editing tools that we have, and decide if it's ready to get into the WordPress 5.8 release. There's a post that has a little more information about that which I will share in the show notes below as well. If you haven't checked out the Gutenberg plugin lately, obviously I think it's a good idea to do that in general, but definitely a good idea to check it out now.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The third thing on our list today is a reminder to check out our most recent block pattern tutorial, I'll share a link to that in the show notes. It's this kind of tips and tricks, tutorial, the “show me how to do it,” kind of thing in the style of <a href="https://css-tricks.com/css-style-guides/">CSS-Tricks</a>. If you or anyone that you know might be interested in sharing a similar style of tutorial, there's a link to a form in that show notes as well so that you can share with us your name and the topic that you're interested in. We'll take a look and see if it's something that we definitely need to make sure our users know how to do. So, that my friends is your small list of big things.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank you for joining in today for the WordPress briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha explores the five groups within the WordPress ecosystem and provides a high-level example of how they interact and support one another. As always, stay tuned for the small list of big things and a contributor highlight.  ]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10099</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-04-12 14:36:23]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-04-12 14:36:23]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:13]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:13]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[who-is-wordpress]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="gutenberg"><![CDATA[Gutenberg]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/04/WP-Briefing-006.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[08:13]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[8MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7950881]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Who Is WordPress?
In this episode, Josepha explores the five groups within the WordPress ecosystem and provides a high-level example of how they interact and support one another. ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/04/WP-Briefing-006.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-04-08]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 7: Your Opinion is Our Opportunity]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/04/your-opinion-is-our-opportunity/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 15:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10171</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha discusses the importance of co-development and testing for the continued growth and maintenance of the WordPress project.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2><strong>Credits</strong></h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2008/10/usability-testing-report-25-and-crazyhorse/">2.5 Usability Testing Report&nbsp;</a></li><li><a href="https://europe.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Europe 2021</a></li><li><a href="https://www.meetup.com/Pune-WordPress-Knowledge-Exchange/events/277520243/">Pune Work Along (Self Study) Meetup</a></li><li><a href="https://fr.wordpress.org/2021/04/09/le-30-avril-2021-rejoignez-nous-pour-un-nouveau-wordpress-translation-day-fr/">French Mini-Translation Day, April 30, 2021</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/2021/04/15/full-site-editing-go-no-go-april-14-2021/">April 14, 2021, Full Site Editing Go/No-Go Demo Recap</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/2021/04/20/full-site-editing-go-no-go-next-steps/">Full Site Editing Go/No-Go Next Steps</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/test/">Test WordPress.org</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>0:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>0:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Prior to Gutenberg, our current multi-year project that is changing the way we see WordPress, another multi-year project changed the way we saw WordPress. Starting in 2008, substantial changes to the WordPress interface came in a series of major releases, starting with WordPress 2.5. That was before my time in the project; I've only ever worked with the current dashboard in WordPress. But, from what I've read, the user testing that would have gone into it was a huge undertaking and very well coordinated. Now, WordPress has not taken on that type of robust testing project since, but starting around 2014 or 2015, a community testing practice was started. I've shared these calls for testing frequently, both on Twitter and in this podcast. But you may not really know why I find the testing program so valuable. So today, I'm going to explore with you the concept of co-developers in open source.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>1:52</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Open source software, like WordPress, is built by the people who show up. There are a few obvious groups when you think of software, the developers, designers, technical writers, folks who monitor the forums, and really, all the teams you find in our WordPress project. Co-developers or co-creators, if you'll join me in making our tent a little bigger, refers to the users of an open source product who actively engage and contribute to the work by using the software and sharing any bugs that they find.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>2:25</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I mentioned this group in the episode about how WordPress improves. Specifically in that episode, I underlined that if you consider users to be part of the collaborative process, as long as people use your product, those people will have opinions about your product’s needs. And today, I'm extending that thought a bit further to say that, as long as there are opinions, there are opportunities.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>2:51</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>When you know what isn't working, you can focus your attention on a solution, you can focus on making sure that you can make it work. The existence of co-creators is one of the great things about open source. No designer or developer or product owner has to know every sort of user to be able to get feedback from them. If they show up, test the software and get their thoughts written down, then you can start to see patterns and common pain points. It is also, unfortunately, one of the great difficulties of being an open source project. After all, if users don't show up, or don't test, or don't write down their feedback, it's impossible to know what worked for them and what didn't. And on top of that, with such a large percentage of the web being supported by WordPress in this case, not every problem is part of a pattern. And not all patterns are part of the current priorities.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>3:54</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Looking beyond that double-edged sword. Let's say that this idea of a co-creator makes sense to you. And more than that, you feel like it describes you. What does it mean for you to show up in WordPress? There are lots of good ways to offer this sort of feedback and contribute to those patterns that can help us see through the fog. So I have for you a mini list and, of course, a bunch of links in the show notes for you.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So some good ways. First, you can participate in any of the dedicated calls for testing. They are short and frequently have a guide. I participate in them and generally find them fun. I say generally because sometimes I also find them frustrating. That's really okay too; the frustrations helped me to identify that I found a problem. And if I can find a problem, then I have saved someone else from finding that problem in the future. The second thing you can do is file a bug report with information about what happened when you ran into a problem and how someone like me could make your bug happen on their site. Bug</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>5:00</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Reporting is one of the things I've grown to really love in my time and open source; I did not love it. At first, I was really scared to do it. I mostly used to send videos of the bugs that I found to other people and ask them to file the bug reports for me. But then, of course, I never knew whether they got fixed or not. So I was scared to do it at first. But once I figured out what makes a “good report,” I felt like I was helping circle hidden treasure on a map or something. I realized also not everyone's excited about finding hidden treasure on a map. But I play video games and finding hidden treasure on maps is, like, a thing.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>5:43</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A third really great way to contribute like this is that you can join any community meeting to learn more about what's happening now and in the future, or just to see what makes WordPress work. As a heads up, these meetings go really fast. And they're all in text. And there's sometimes, but not all the time, a little bit of jargon that you have to head to your favorite search engine to find. But I sit in on about half of them myself and get a lot of really good information about things that I've been wondering about, things that looked broken, but actually are functioning exactly the way that they should. And I just didn't want them to function that way. And more often than not, I found out that something that I thought was broken, was already identified and being fixed. Those are three great ways to show up and help give feedback that helps make WordPress better and more functional for more people.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There are also a few other ways that we see people trying to share that feedback that don't work quite as well. And I'm going to touch on a few of them just because it's important to know, as you're trying to figure out how to get started with this. The first one is just tweeting your frustrations, and I get it like that's literally what Twitter is for.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>7:03</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But also it's hard to create a block from “I am frustrated, behold my hateful rhetoric.” Not that any of you, my dear listeners, ever tweet hateful rhetoric. Still, that is really hard for anyone to figure out what was actually wrong in that moment. Another thing that is not the most functional way to give feedback is review brigading. The Internet rewards this kind of behavior, but I have found at least for WordPress, those false positives and false negatives can be really confusing for our new users. And the third way, that's not our best way, and probably is the least best way, is just by giving up and not telling anyone what broke for you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>7:45</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I know that I already said it's not possible to fix everyone's problems. But while it's not possible to fix everyone's problems the moment they get shared, it's also truly impossible to fix any problems that no one knows exist. And so giving up and not sharing an issue so that we can identify it as part of a pattern of problems is probably the least effective way to help us help you get your problem solved.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>8:13</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This brings me back to the question of the value of WordPress users as co creators in the development process. As WordPress grows, both in usage as a CMS and in participation as a community, it's important for us to shed the idea that software creation is only about what literally can be done to code or what literally can be done to core or what literally can be done to the CMS. It's also important for us to constantly remind ourselves that the best outcomes are the result of collaboration with the people who use WordPress the most. I know that not every type of user we have is showing up to give us feedback about where WordPress doesn't work for them. And I would love to see more feedback that helps us to figure out where our patterns are.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>9:03</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So the bottom line is this without user feedback that has some clarity of what was expected versus what happened, the work to make a good choice involves a whole lot of guessing. So since open source software is built by the people who show up, I hope this gives you an idea of how you can show up and help improve the tool that powers your sites.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>9:32</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us to today's community highlight every episode or so I share either a great story of WordPress success or a great story of a WordPress contributor who helped some folks along the way. Today's <a href="https://twitter.com/trishacodes/status/1357382647274762244">community highlight</a> comes from @trishacodes who shared one of her early to WordPress mentors. She says “@RianRietveld was such an encouragement and helped me find the courage to speak up.” I have had myself many conversations with <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/rianrietveld/">Rian</a>, and that rings true for me as well.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>10:00</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us to the moment you've all been waiting for, the small list of big things. It's actually kind of a medium list. Today, I've got four whole things to share with you all. The first thing on my list is that WordCamp Europe is coming, that will be June 7th through the 10th. It's a multi-day online event. I will share in the show notes a link to the main website; there you can get an idea of what will happen, the schedule, and get your hands on some tickets so that you can get it in your calendar and prepare yourselves.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing I want to share is for all of our polyglots out there. The French team is planning a translation day coming up on April 30. I will share a link to that as well so that you can get an idea of what that takes if you're feeling like you want to do some translation work. The third thing I want to share is that the Indian community in Pune actually started a new meetup series. It is a translation work along self-study - also for all of our polyglots out there. I would love to see as many people as are interested in both learning about how to do translations and certainly translating WordPress get registered for that. A final thing I want to share with you all is that if you are curious about what full site editing features will be included in the 5.8 release, that's the WordPress release that's coming out in the middle of July, you can check out my recap and recording of the demo that was held with Matt, Matias, and the rest of the team. There’s are also a number of other posts of next step ideas that I will share in the show notes as well.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>11:51</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That, my friends, is your small list of big things. Thank you for joining in today for the WordPress briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha discusses the importance of co-development and testing for the continued growth and maintenance of the WordPress project. ]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10171</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-04-26 15:24:28]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-04-26 15:24:28]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:22]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:22]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[your-opinion-is-our-opportunity]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/04/WP-Briefing-007.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12:34]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12131727]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[Your Opinion is Our Opportunity:
In this episode, Josepha discusses the importance of co-development and testing for the continued growth and maintenance of the WordPress project. ]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/04/WP-Briefing-007.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-04-23]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 8: The Commons of Images]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/05/the-commons-of-images/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 12:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10266</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha is joined by the co-founder and project lead of WordPress, Matt Mullenweg. Tune in to hear Matt and Josepha discuss the relaunch of CC Search (Openverse) in WordPress and the facets of the open source ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Openverse Repositories </strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Catalog:&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/wordpress/openverse-catalog">https://github.com/wordpress/openverse-catalog</a></li><li>API:&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/wordpress/openverse-api">https://github.com/wordpress/openverse-api</a></li><li>Frontend:&nbsp;<a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/wordpress/openverse-frontend">https://github.com/wordpress/openverse-frontend</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Tech Stack Outline</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><strong>Frontend</strong>- Languages: <ul><li>JavaScript, CSS/SCSS</li><li>Libraries/Services: Vue.js, Nuxt.js#&nbsp;</li></ul></li><li><strong>API</strong>- Languages: <ul><li>Python, PostgreSQL</li><li>Libraries/Services: Django, Elasticsearch, Redis</li></ul></li><li><strong>Catalogue</strong>- Languages: <ul><li>Python, PostgreSQL</li><li>Libraries/Services: Apache Airflow, PySpark</li></ul></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Join the WordPress Slack instance, #openverse</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress Briefing. This is usually the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas is behind the WordPress open source project. Today, I have a little bit of a different topic. It's still WordPress, it's still open source, but it's kind of peering into some stuff for the future as opposed to looking at where we are today or how we got to where we are today.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:36</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>You might have recently seen an announcement from Matt that CC Search is joining the WordPress project. This is a really exciting thing for open source, for sure, and definitely, from my perspective, for WordPress. And so I invited Matt to join me today to take a look at what he had in mind with bringing that particular project into our project and what we have in mind for the future. And so, today, this is the WordPress Briefing with Matt and Josepha. And I hope you enjoy the conversation we had. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>01:22</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So, we recently announced for WordPress that we essentially acquired CC Search, a project that's been part of Creative Commons. And they recently chose a different kind of roadmap for the work they're doing in the future. And so it seemed like a really great opportunity to bring this tool and this, I don't know, this kind of experience for our users into the WordPress project. So Matt, what are your thoughts about how, like this commitment to images with CC licenses, with Creative Commons licenses, can impact WordPress and how we work in the open web.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>02:09</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I think it's pretty exciting because Creative Commons exists to do for media, you know, images, audio, etc., what open source has done for code. And so for people who choose to want to donate their creative work under these licenses, much like anyone who contributes a plugin, or code or documentation or translations for WordPress, now people for whom their method of expression is, let's say, photography, can put that into the comments like literally, I like why it's called the Creative Commons, it's such a good name. It can be accessed within everyone's dashboard for WordPress. And those images can start to really be part of the fabric of the web the same way that code that runs WordPress or its plugins is part of the fabric of the web.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>02:57</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For anyone who's listening who's not actually already familiar with this concept of the tragedy of the commons, do you want to give us the elevator pitch of what that means and why it's so important for WordPress to try to counterbalance that in our work?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>03:12</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Sure, the tragedy of the commons, you know, I think the canonical example is as a shared field in a town, and it doesn't belong to anyone, so anyone can use it. And when too many farmers took their sheep there, they would overeat the grass, and then there was no more grass left because it was being overutilized, and there was no one owning the field to say, Hey, we need to practice a more sustainable amount of sheep. grass in</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>03:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Put more grass in there.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>03:41</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So basically, the idea is like a shared resource that gets overused and then disappears. With software, we have the opportunity to have the opposite, which is a wealth of comments where every person using the thing actually has the opportunity to make it a little bit better. And that is really beauty of like Wikipedia, open source where every person using it might contribute a small fix, or a translation or a bug report or tell a friend about it, or basically be part of making this thing better, which you know, WordPress is history is very much an example of, and then as it gets better, more people want to use it. And the beautiful thing about software is you can have economics of abundance versus the economics of scarcity. There's not one field used, but every additional incremental user of WordPress makes this community stronger and creates a larger market for the products inside it. So those types of dynamics can have the opposite of the tragedy of the commons.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>04:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Absolutely. I love this idea that you brought it up in your question, not your question, in your answer right at the top. I love this idea of acknowledging that code isn't the only fabric available in open source and certainly not the only fabric of the internet as we know it. This idea of like, let's bring Creative Commons licensed images into a more long-term space for WordPress. Do you think that that at some point can apply to videos and other sorts of audio files?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>05:21</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Absolutely. There already is a ton of Creative Commons licensed content out there that people can use. But there's a discoverability problem, you know? Each individual image or audio file or video is, is a little bit of an island. So that's why it's so important that there's the equivalent of a search engine that allows people to discover all the great stuff that's out there. And what happens today is there's stock photography sites, some of which used to be Creative Commons-based, but many have moved away from that. So they essentially relicense their user contributions. Or people, if we're being real, people just go to Google images, and they might utilize images that they don't actually have rights to. It's not the end of the world, but it's not ideal. And so we can create this really compelling directory experience of imagery, which people have chosen to share and want to be used. I think that's a much better outcome than the equivalent of piracy.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>06:21</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yeah, yeah, absolutely. So I leapt right into this and didn't really give any context to what CC Search is or anything, but for anyone who is not familiar with this tool already, CC Search is, as Matt mentioned, a search engine that currently is focused specifically on images that use open licenses. The Creative Commons licenses are like the content-specific version of GPL for code, which is a really big deal, I think. If wishes were fishes, Matt, and you had your total hope ahead of you, what is your hope for the relaunch of this product and this tool in WordPress?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>07:15</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Well, first and foremost, I think we can improve the experience of designing and contributing themes and then modifying them with this really fantastic image directory if we're able to build it in the media library. And lots of plugins like Jetpack do some version of this. I think that Jetpack uses Pexels or one of the proprietary, but open libraries. And so we can make it fully, like you said, the equivalent of GPL and open source, all the better. I think longer-term, I'd love to have a way for people who are adding media to the WordPress site to set it to be available under a Creative Commons license. So just to make it easy and built-in for people to create more Creative Commons license imagery. And then, you know, with the integration of Gutenberg and other things, we can make it easy for other people to use it and credit back the original author if they choose to. And what we find is that even though with CC0, which is essentially a kind of like putting something into the public domain, credit is not required. If you make it the default to link back to the original photographer, author, most people believe that because they like creating things that they use. So you get the best of both worlds; you have the freedom of use for any purpose, including not requiring the credit. But then, just by having it by default, when you insert one of these images, a lot of people are going to leave that and link back to the original author, which I think is also really cool. Like you're not required to have a credit link on WordPress, but most people leave the Powered BY WordPress on there.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>08:45</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>One of the interesting areas, you mentioned Pexels in this case. One of those interesting areas that we, as a project, can really explore here is how to make it so that the metadata gives you confidence in the origin of the image. Like I don't believe that there are any set standards for that. I've just started my research, obviously, because they're brand new to us, but I just don't think there are any standards available there. And, I think that there is an opportunity for WordPress as a true supporter of the open web to help change the fact that we don't have that’s one of the main competitive disadvantages that open source libraries have been trying to combat and especially with Unsplash, who eventually did get purchased by Getty Images. Still, I feel like part of what must have driven that decision to change the licensing terms had to be that they are up against that behemoth of Getty Images where people know where the things came from. They know where the images came from, and they can trust that lineage and model releases and all that stuff. I'm just really interested to see how we can; I don't know; I hate to say dignify contributors who are offering their contributions to open source in this way. But, it also is kind of that there's no sense in saying that just because you did not accept payment from getting images, your photos weren't any good, or your images did not have an excellent path to where they are housed at that moment.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>10:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I mean, it's really fun to contribute to something larger than yourself. And for many folks, you know, their gift, their craft is something like photography. And so there's always going to be the sort of paid marketplaces and, and something like Shutterstock, I think really fantastic companies and services. I think a marketplace for paid content. But we just want to make an alternative, so those who want to donate their work to the world, much like engineers, and designers, and translators of WordPress, donate their work some of that effort to the world, they can do so. Right now, there are some places for that, but we're going to try to create one that is fully open, has no advertising, has an open API. So other CMSs can access it too.&nbsp; You know, we're going to try to bring the WordPress philosophy to this space.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>11:29</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Gosh, I just love that. While we're on the question of contributing to something bigger than yourself, bringing the WordPress philosophy into this space, how do you think CC Search will impact the current media library and how WordPress handles media in general? Or do you have an idea about how it will impact that? Sometimes we don't know until we get in?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>11:53</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yeah, I think within Gutenberg, the idea of adding an image from an online library or a search is something we've wanted to do for a while. But either the licensing made it a little tricky, or, you know, some of the sites that did have open things, maybe the site itself had like a lot of advertising or pop-ups or things like that. So by having this hosted by wordpress.org, we'll have a clean, open source, and ad-free place that people can access. I suppose it's also worth saying that CC Search, which we're rebranding as Openverse, is actually all the code behind is open source as well. So there is going to be a new project on WordPress's GitHub that will be this open source search engine. So that's also part of the contributions; we'll be pointing this search engine to try to index and collect Creative Commons license media, but perhaps it could also provide a base for someone else wanting to build a different characters engine or just host Openverse themselves and run it themselves; that is totally fine.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>13:00</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I should probably mention, for any of the WP Briefing listeners who are contributing to the WordPress project itself, there is a brand new team that we're working on building, and for one wander over and welcome everybody, we are welcoming in an open source community into our open source community. And so, of course, we want to make sure that they know how to get around and feel welcome in the space. But also, anything that you are interested in helping to contribute to that particular project, I think would be helpful. WordPress is big; we have a long history. And so I think I feel confident in saying that, if I were on that team that's bringing in this new tool, I would hope that there were some OG WordPressers, who were available to help me discover the ins and outs of things, especially as its 18 years of us.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>14:04</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yeah, it's also a new technology stack. So let's say you want to be involved in WordPress, but your expertise is more on the Python side, or Elastic Search or something like that. We now have a project where people who are into that or want to learn about it can get involved. Because, of course, you know, contributing and being involved with open source is probably the best way to learn a technology, better than any college degree.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>14:28</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I was just talking to some folks about that; our active learning opportunities and our passive learning opportunities get into a different balance as we get older. And active learning opportunities are for real in school, right? And our passive learning opportunities where you get to look at someone else's code, you get to review proposals on user flows, and things are harder and harder to come by unless you happen to be in an open source project where we're just working on that in the open all day, every day. And I'll put a link to the repos in the show notes, and also, I'll include a list of the tech stack that we're looking at there, just so that no one has to like, chase it down. But yeah, I'm excited about this new integration, not only for the CMS but also for the community.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>15:26</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And the whole library will be available to any plug-in who wants to call to it. And like we said, even other CMSs, much like we designed Gutenberg to be able to be used by other CMSs, how cool would it be if Drupal or Joomla or others were also able to leverage this library and allow their users to contribute to it as well?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>15:47</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yeah, absolutely. Absolutely. There is a burning question that I feel like we probably should just go ahead and answer here. I've been asked a few times, and I think you have been asked a few times whether this is an actual acquisition. And If yes, then what entity is it under? Is it under the WordPress Foundation? Is it under Automattic?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>16:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It's a little complicated because, as you know, WordPress.org is not part of the Foundation. So basically, Automattic paid Creative Commons, the nonprofit. They will essentially redirect the old URL, so old links to Creative Commons Search won't break. And we ended up hiring some of the people that they were parting ways with into Automattic. And then we put that open source code, and we'll run the service on WordPress.org, and then those we hired, Automattic hired, will contribute to WordPress.org and the open source projects that power what we're calling Openverse now.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>16:54</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I am.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>16:56</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That's kind of an acquisition, but also from a nonprofit, and then going into something, which is not a nonprofit, but is open source and sort of freely available, which is WordPress.org, the website.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>17:06</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yeah, that has been hard for me to answer because you're right, it's not like it was donated to WordPress or something. But everything that we're doing is being donated back to the project, and of course, hopefully, really living into that WordPress ethos that we have of giving back to, to the project, something that made your work and your life better. So there's some, some finger-crossing going on in there.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>17:37</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>We could have skipped some of the steps because the code was open source; we could have just used it or something like that. But it was also a good opportunity, I think, to support the Creative Commons organization. And like we said, as part of that donation, there'll be redirecting Creative Commons Search to WordPress.org. And honestly, we don't need that, but it just from the point of view of keeping links workings, which is a big passion of mine. I like that none of the links will break or things to the Creative Commons Search, which I think has been around for... I don't actually know the exact timeline, but a very long time. It's been part of the internet for a long time. So we're happy that it can now continue and be something that can plausibly be around for many decades to come.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>18:23</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Yeah, we're going to build ourselves a little sustainable program around this project, and it's going to be beautiful; I'm excited.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>18:31</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I did want to give everybody a cultural heads up. When I say crossing my fingers, I know that for some of our cultures, that means I was lying. That is not what I'm saying—crossing my fingers and moving forward on this with a lot of hope.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>18:51</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I tried to be careful about my local idioms when I'm talking to folks who don't know that I'm from Arkansas, so I sometimes say weird things. But I've given up on y'all, for instance, like that has made its way right back into my language.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>19:09</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Y'all is great. In Texas, we had a funny thing, which maybe applies to you now, which is "more nervous than a long-tailed cat in a room full of rocking chairs." I bet you haven't heard that one.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>19:21</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have not, but I love it, and I'm going to fold it into my personal vocabulary for later use.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>19:30</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The response to this has been overwhelmingly positive, and I know that I am incredibly positive. I just mentioned like I'm moving forward through this with hope, even though there's a lot of stuff that I don't actually know about how we can implement it. I have never brought an existing open source community into an open source community that I'm currently working with. So there's a lot of learning to be done in there. But, from your side Matt, like, are there any things that you are feeling anxiously hopeful about for this? Anything that you hope is right, but you're not sure about?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>20:14</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Oh, this is just the first step of many. So just having the search engine, is I think good to provide a service to the internet. But where we can really leverage it is those next steps we already talked about, which is really building out the API and integrating the API with the WordPress admin to make it easily accessible within people's dashboards. And the Gutenberg blocks to embed these images, quickly and easily, and with all the proper credit and everything. And then the next step, which was probably the one I'm most excited about, which is enabling folks to contribute to the Creative Commons. And by that, I mean the Commons of Images, which have open licenses and are encouraged for reuse and remixing and all those sorts of great things. And I think that anything we can do to increase more of that stuff on the internet also enables a lot of creativity and innovation.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>21:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>All right. Well, that was an excellent conversation. I am really excited about this. I want to, for my work, just say a huge welcome to the folks over at CC Search and our brand new group around Openverse, and a big thanks to the folks over at the Creative Commons group. Matt, do you have anything else you want to share with any of our audience?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>21:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>No, I feel great that we could support the Creative Commons, keep this going for the open internet, and so excited to work alongside the folks who have been working on Openverse and take it to the next iterations and the next level.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>21:56</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Beautiful. Well, Matt, thank you so much for joining me today. This was a wonderful conversation. My friends, this has been Matt Mullenweg, WordPress project co-founder, and project lead.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Matt Mullenweg&nbsp; </strong>22:08</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank you so much for having me.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>22:17</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank you for tuning in today to the WordPress Briefing. I hope that conversation made you as excited as I am about this new adventure that we're embarking on with CC Search and that whole team. I'm going to put in the show notes a few links to where you can find them, where they're doing their work, what you can collaborate on, and also some notes about the tech stack that goes into it. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy.Thanks again for joining me and I'll see you in a couple of weeks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha is joined by the co-founder and project lead of WordPress, Matt Mullenweg. Tune in to hear Matt and Josepha discuss the relaunch of CC Search (Openverse) in WordPress and the facets of the open source ecosystem. ]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10266</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-05-10 12:00:42]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-05-10 12:00:42]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:31]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-24 23:08:31]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[the-commons-of-images]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/05/WP-Briefing-008.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23:12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[21MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[22345396]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[spay_email]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_mess]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[The Commons of Images: In this episode, Josepha is joined by the co-founder and project lead of WordPress, Matt Mullenweg. Tune into hear Matt and Josepha discuss the relaunch of CC Search (Openverse) in WordPress.org.]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_is_tweetstorm]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/05/WP-Briefing-008.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 9: The Cartography of WordPress]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/05/episode-9-the-cartography-of-wordpress/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 11:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10373</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy provides a map of how to navigate WordPress teams and communication channels, along with her small list of big things.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://www.meetup.com/pro/wordpress/">https://www.meetup.com/pro/wordpress/</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://make.wordpress.org/" target="_blank">https://make.wordpress.org/</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://make.wordpress.org/chat/" target="_blank">https://chat.wordpress.org/</a></li><li><a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="https://make.wordpress.org/">Make WordPress</a> Slack</li><li><a href="https://europe.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Europe</a>, June 7-9</li><li><a href="https://japan.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Japan</a>, June 20-26</li><li>The Sixth<a href="https://make.wordpress.org/test/2021/05/12/fse-program-testing-call-6-stick-the-landing-pages/"> call for testing</a> on Template Editing&nbsp;</li><li>The <a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2021/05/dropping-support-for-internet-explorer-11/">upcoming drop of Internet Explorer 11 support</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Joseph Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:40</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Almost every episode of this podcast, you can hear me invite you to join in the WordPress project, to contribute back, to get involved. And I'm sure that every time I say that there's at least one of you who's like “Yes. Challenge accepted!” And you wade in sight unseen, to immerse yourselves in the cheerful cacophony of open source at scale that is WordPress. You see before you all 158 ways you can start contributing and you are exhilarated by this lostness. This you think, is the lostness of infinite possibility. And for you, I'm really thankful. My work here today would not be possible if it weren't for the brave souls who leap into something with hope as their primary plan and tactic. You are heroes, and I thank you very much for your service. For everyone else, I'm going to give you a quick tour of where WordPress collaborates and a little bit of how they collaborate. We'll cover the Make network, the Making WordPress Slack, events for WordPress, and a rundown of the teams.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>First, the Make network. The Make network of sites can be found at make.wordpress.org. That page includes information on most of our teams. Teams like Core and Design and Community. All of those teams require some technical skills since we're a project built around a piece of software. However, some require a little more than others. You can think of this set of sites as the desk of each team in the WordPress project. It's where they update each other, where they host discussions, where they refine proposals, and where they coordinate admin tasks. Contributors can write posts on most sites in the network as long as they follow the guidelines and best practices. And anyone with a wordpress.org profile can join in discussions in the comments. Most work on the Make network is asynchronous, and discussions stay open for a long enough time to allow anyone in the world to weigh in when they have the time. It's how we try to remember that we are a globally-minded project.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second area is the Making WordPress Slack instance. The Making WordPress Slack instance can be found at wordpress.slack.com, and it requires an account that is associated with your wordpress.org profile. Each team in the project has a channel, although not all channels in that Slack instance, represent a standalone team. You can think of this Slack instance as a set of conference rooms. It's where contributors connect, gain a more nuanced understanding of problems that we're trying to solve. They host synchronous meetings and also coordinate working groups.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>03:31</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Contributors can post in most channels, although there are a few that are restricted. We don't have any social channels in this Slack instance, but most WordPress-ers do tend to find friends that they connect with. The work done here is synchronous, and most meetings last about an hour. There are about 35+ meetings a week, so you can basically always find someone around.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The last area we work is actually at WordPress events. Word Camps and WordPress meetups happen all over the world. Unless there's a global pandemic, then they're kind of all over the computer and at all times of day and night. You can keep track of those on wordcamp.org or on WordPress’s meetup page, which I've linked in the notes below. These events bring together all sorts of facets of the WordPress project. And they are an event where local WordPress communities aim to connect, inspire and educate each other. There's always someone at these events, who knows a little bit more about WordPress than you do. If you're headed to want to learn more about contribution, look out for any that have a contributor day or are hosting a contribution drive. These are clearly synchronous events. And when we do get back to doing them in person, they're also tied to physical locations. When we get back to them, I encourage you to find one that's close to you. They are incredibly valuable.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Okay, so that's the map of the area. Those are the three big places where we get this stuff done. Let's do a quick map of the teams themselves. If you're a developer and you're looking to work inside the technology space, work with code a bit, then your best chances for teams are Core and all of its related components. They're like 50 components, including core editor and various other things. There's also the Mobile team WP CLI, the Tide team, Security, our brand new team, Openverse, and Meta. Those all take a fairly high amount of code knowledge to contribute there.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you're more into design and product work, then we have a few teams for that as well. There's of course, the Design team, but we also have Accessibility, Test, Triage, Polyglots kind of falls in there for me. But if you are a programs person, and we're talking like programs, getting people together programs, not programs, as in programming or code. So if you're a programs person, you're looking more at the Community team, at the Themes team, the Plugin team, Polyglots, again, Training support, probably a number of others that have like program components in it as well.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you are really interested in learning more about contributor experience, which is how we build tools, and again, programs for all of the contributors who are showing up, then the teams for you will be teams like Meta and Documentation, Hosting, the Community team, the Training team, arguably any team that has a program as part of it is considered contributor experience because that's how we help our contributors know what to do, what not to do, how to help them get onboarded, find their way, stuff like that.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And if you're more in the communications area of things, we have quite a few teams there as well. We do have Marketing, of course, but also I think that Support ends up in our communications area, WordPress TV, obviously ends up in communications. But I think Training, Meta, Documentation, and arguably, maybe also Testing ends up in that space as well.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I realize that there are a handful of teams that I mentioned multiple times, especially Polyglots, Support, Test, Triage, Meta, Community. The reason they end up in a number of different places is that all of those teams also have a fair amount of admin and infrastructure stuff that goes into the WordPress project and community as a whole. So it touches a lot of other teams, and so they get a lot of mentions. All right. So WordPress adventurers, you now have a beginner's map. I hope it helps, and I hope we see you around the community.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>07:54</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you're still with me, that brings us today to my small list of big things. I've got four things for you, and I'm excited about all of them. The first two are events actually. WordCamp Europe is coming up from June seventh through the ninth. It will include a presentation from the WordPress project co-founder, Matt Mullenweg, so I encourage you to hop over, grab a ticket to check out the rest of the sessions that are happening while you're there. The next one is WordCamp, Japan, which is happening June 20th through the 26th. And you heard that right that is seven whole days of WordCamp. It's a little bit of a different format than we normally take, but it's five days actually of contribution on ten specific projects. Then that's bookended on either side of those contribution days, with full days of sessions. There's some in English, but it's primarily in Japanese. But either way, I think it's going to be a really excellent event, and I encourage everyone to check it out.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The rest of my list is not events. We have opened our sixth call for testing, it's specifically looking at the template editing mode for Full Site Editing. It is an iteration on one of our earliest tests for the Full Site Editing outreach program. And so it has incorporated a lot of the feedback that we got in that test the first time around. So if you look at that test, which by the way, are all guided, if you've never tested anything before, don't let this scare you. It's really well written, it's got a good guide on it and, and also allows for a little bit of exploration. But if you participated in the landing page test that we did early on, this is the follow-up to that. It incorporates a lot of the feedback that we got, so this is closing that feedback loop and I encourage you to stop by and participate in that test. It will be linked in the show notes and also I tweet about it a bit so you can run over there and find it also.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>&nbsp;WordPress is dropping support for Internet Explorer 11. That's happening over the summer, so around the middle of July is when that's going to happen. If you've been using WordPress for a while you've been getting notifications. If you happen to get to WordPress with IE11, letting you know that that this particular browser is reaching the end of its life for support in general on the web, but now WordPress also is making the choice to drop support for that. And so there's a post out on wordpress.org/news, which I will also link to in the show notes in case you have not heard about this yet. It shouldn't have any immediate and noticeable effects on anyone who's visiting a site that's built using WordPress. There might be a few things in the dashboard that don't work if you are administering a WordPress site from IE11. So there's a lot of good information in that post. Give it a read and if you have questions, always feel free to stop by the Core chat and ask those as we go.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And that my friends is your smallest of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress Briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in a couple of weeks!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy provides a map of how to navigate WordPress teams and communication channels, along with her small list of big things.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10373</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-05-24 11:55:14]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-05-24 11:55:14]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-05-24 11:55:15]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-05-24 11:55:15]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[episode-9-the-cartography-of-wordpress]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[17810800]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/05/WP-Briefining-009.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11:49]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/05/WP-Briefining-009.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-05-21]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11402806]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 10: Finding the Good In Disagreement]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/06/episode-10-finding-the-good-in-disagreement/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10424</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>To Agree, disagree, and everything in-between. In this episode, Josepha talks about forming opinions and decision-making in the WordPress project.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://www.oprah.com/spirit/suzy-welchs-rule-of-10-10-10-decision-making-guide/all">10/10/10 Rule</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_management#The_Eisenhower_Method">The Eisenhower Matrix&nbsp;</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minimax">The Maximin Strategy&nbsp;</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://europe.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Europe</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://japan.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Japan</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/5-8/">WordPress 5.8 Development Cycle</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress Briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of some of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project and the community around it, as well as get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Joseph Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:40</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>For anyone who has ever organized something, whether it's a social event, a school project, or an annual family gathering, you know that there are many different opinions. The more opinions you have, the more likely people don't see eye to eye. And before you know it, you've got some disagreements. Some things make disagreements worse, like imbalance of information, lack of showing your work, and sometimes just “too many cooks in the kitchen,” to use a regional phrase. Frankly, sometimes it seems like the second you have more than one cook in your kitchen, you're going to get some disagreements. But I think that's a healthy thing. WordPress is huge. And there are huge numbers of people contributing to WordPress or any other open source project you want to name. So there's a lot of stuff available to disagree about. If we never saw anyone pointing out an area that wasn't quite right, there would probably be something wrong. If you, like me, think that a healthy tension of collaborative disagreement can be useful when approached thoughtfully, then this quick start guide is for you.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Step one, prepare to host a discussion. This is, by the way, just the hardest step out there. You have to take a little time to figure out what problem you're solving with the solution you're suggesting, any goals that it relates to, and then figure out what the bare minimum best outcome would be and what the wildest dreams magic wand waving outcome would be. And you have to be honest with yourself.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Step two, host the discussion. The venue will be different for different discussions, but you see a lot of these on team blogs or within the actual tickets where work is being done. Wherever you're hosting it, state the problem, state your idea for the solution and ask for what you missed. If you're hosting a discussion in person, like in a town hall format, this can be hard. And generally, hosting discussions in an in-person or voice call or zoom call kind of way is hard. So if you have an opportunity to start doing this in text first and level your way up to in person, that's my recommendation.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Step three is to summarize the discussion and post a decision if possible. So organizing a big discussion into main points is a really good practice for the people you're summarizing it for and yourself. It helps you to confirm your understanding, and it also gives you the chance to pair other solutions with the problem and goals you outlined in step one. If a different solution solves the same problem but with less time or effort, it's worth taking a second look with less time or effort. There’s something that I say to WordPress contributors frequently, and that is there are a lot of yeses. There are a lot of right ways to do things and only a few clear wrong ways to do things. So be open-minded about whether or not someone else's right way to do things could still achieve the goals you're trying to accomplish with your solution. A note on step three where I said, “and post the decision if possible.” Sometimes you're the person to make that decision, but sometimes you are not the person who can give something the green light, and so you're preparing a recommendation. Whether you're making a decision or a recommendation, sometimes you may experience a little decision-making paralysis. I know I do. So here are a few of the tools that I use.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you're avoiding the decision, use the 10/10/10 rule; it can help you figure out if you're stuck on a short-term problem. If there are too many good choices, use the Eisenhower Matrix that can help you to prioritize objectively. If there are too many bad choices, use the Maximin strategy. It can help you to identify how to minimize any potential negative impacts.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Okay, so you've considered your position. You’ve discussed everything. You summarized the big points. Maybe you also worked your way through to a recommendation or a decision. What about everyone who disagreed with the decision? Or have you made a recommendation, and it wasn't accepted? How do you deal with that? That's where “disagree and commit” shows up. This phrase was made popular by the folks over at Amazon, I think. But it first showed up, I believe at Sun Microsystems as this phrase, “agreeing, commit, disagree and commit or get out of the way.”</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>05:34</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Disagree and commit as a concept works pretty well when everyone agrees on the vision and the goals, but not necessarily how to get to those goals. We've had moments in recent history where folks we're not able to agree, we’re not able to commit, and so then left the project. I hate when that happens. I want people to thrive in this community for the entire length of their careers. But I also understand that situation shows up in the top five learnings of open source when you no longer have interest in the project and handed it off to a competent successor. So there it is - disagreements in open source in WordPress.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As with so many of the things I discuss on this podcast, this is incredibly complex and nuanced in practice. Taking an argument, distilling facts from feelings, and adjusting frames of reference until the solution is well informed and risk-balanced. That is a skill set unto itself. But one that increases the health of any organization. I’ll share that list of references and general materials in the show notes, including a link explaining each of those decision-making tools that I shared. I'm also going to include the contributor training module on decision-making in the WordPress project. It's got excellent information. It's part of a series of modules that I asked team reps to take and sponsored contributors. I don't require it from anyone, but I do hope that it is useful for you. Also, speaking of useful for you, if you are just here for leadership insights, I included some hot takes after the outro music for you. It's like an Easter egg, but I just told you about it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>07:33</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And that brings us to our small list of big things! First off, WordCamp Europe is happening this we; I hope that everybody has an opportunity to attend. If you still haven't gotten your tickets, they are free, and I think there are still a few left. I will include a link in the show notes as well. There's going to be a little demo with Matt Mullenweg and Matias Ventura on the WordPress 5.8 release that's coming up. And then kind of a retrospective discussion between Matt and Brian Krogsgard. I encourage you to join; I think it's going to be very interesting.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>There's also WordCamp, Japan coming up June 20 through 26th. I mentioned it last time -&nbsp; it has a big section of contributing and contribution time. So if you're looking to get started, some projects are laid out, and I encourage you to take a look at that as well.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The new thing on this list, and I don't know how new It is, in general, I hope it's not too new to you, is that WordPress 5.8 release is reaching its beta one milestone on June 8th, so right in the middle of WordCamp Europe. I encourage every single theme developer, plugin developer that we have, agency owners that we have to really take a look at this release and dig into testing it. It's a gigantic release. And I have so many questions about what will work and will not work once we get it into a broader testing area. We've been doing a lot of testing in the outreach program. But it's always helpful to get people who are using WordPress daily in their jobs to really give a good solid test to the beta product to the beta package. And put it all through its paces for us.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So, that my friends, is your small list of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress Briefing. I'm your host Josepha Haden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in a couple of weeks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>10:09</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hey there, you must be here because I told you about this totally not hidden easter egg about my hot takes on organizational health; I have three for you. And if you've ever worked with me, none of this will surprise you. But if you haven't worked with me, hopefully, it kind of gives you some idea about how I approach all of this a bit differently. So, number one, critical feedback is the sign of a healthy organization. And I will never be dissuaded from that opinion. A complete lack of dissent doesn't look like “alignment.” To me, that looks like fear. And it goes against the open source idea that many eyes make all bugs shallow.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Tip number two, a bit of tension is good, a bit of disagreement is good. The same thing that I say about women in tech, we're not all the same. And if we were, then we wouldn't need to collaborate anyway. But diversity, whether that's the diversity of thought or of a person or of experience, just doesn't happen without some misunderstandings. It's how we choose to grow through those misunderstandings that make all the difference for the type of organization we are.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And hot take number three, changing your mind isn't flip-flopping or hypocritical. I think that's a sign of growth and willingness to hear others. I like to think of my embarrassment at past bad decisions - as the sore muscles of a learning brain. And I, again, probably won't be dissuaded from that opinion. Although, you know, if I'm sticking true to changing your mind some flip-flopping or hypocritical, maybe I will, but you can always try to, to give me the counter-argument for that, and we'll see how it goes. Thank you for joining me for my little public easter egg.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10424</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-06-07 12:22:06]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-07 12:22:06]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-19 17:25:54]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-19 17:25:54]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[episode-10-finding-the-good-in-disagreement]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-06-04]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11484726]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/06/WP-Briefing-010.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11:54]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/06/WP-Briefing-010.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 11: WordCamp Europe 2021 in Review]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/06/episode-11-wordcamp-europe-2021-in-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 12:33:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10837</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy does a mini deep dive into WordCamp Europe 2021, specifically the conversation between the project’s co-founder, Matt Mullenweg, and Brian Krogsgard formerly of PostStatus. Tune in to hear her take and for this episode’s small list of big things.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References </h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2021/06/gutenberg-highlights/">Gutenberg Highlights&nbsp;</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o-IvKy3322k&amp;t=12428s">Matt Mullenweg in conversation with Brian Krogsgard&nbsp;</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/core/5-8/">5.8 Development Cycle</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://japan.wordcamp.org/2021/">WordCamp Japan</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://europe.wordcamp.org/2021/a-recap-on-wceu-2021/">A recap on WCEU 2021</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 00:10</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress Briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project, some insights into the community that supports it, and get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 00:40</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A couple of weeks ago, we hosted WordCamp Europe and had the double pleasure of a demo that showed us a bit about the future of WordPress and an interview that looked back while also looking a bit forward. If you haven't seen the demo, it was beautiful. And I've included a link to it in the show notes. And if you haven't heard the interview, there were a few specific moments that I'd like to take the time to delve into a little more. Brian Krogsgard, in his conversation with Matt Mullenweg, brought up three really interesting points. I mean, he brought up a lot of interesting points, but there were three that I would particularly like to look into today. The first was about balance. The second was about cohesion. And the third was about those we leave behind.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 01:24</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So first is this question of balance. Brian brought this up in the context of the overall economic health of the WordPress ecosystem. And in that particular moment, he talked about companies that are coming together, companies that are merging. And in Matt's answer, the part that I found the most interesting was when he said, "the point at which there is the most commercial opportunity is also the point at which there is the most opportunity for short-termism. He went on to talk about the importance of long-term thinking and collective thinking about what makes us, and us here means probably the WordPress project, more vibrant and vital in 10 or 20 or 30 years. One of the things that he specifically called out in that answer was the responsibility of larger companies in the ecosystem. For instance, like Automattic, to commit fully to giving back, there are many ways now that companies can give back to WordPress so that we all replenish the Commons. They can pay for volunteer contributors' time; they can create and sponsor entire teams through the Five for the Future program. They can contribute time through our outreach program. And they can even contribute to WordPress's ability to own our own voice by engaging their audience's awareness of what's next in WordPress, or whatever. And I know this balance, this particular balance of paid contributors or sponsored contributors, compared to our volunteer contributors or self-sponsored contributors; I know that this balance is one that people keep an eagle eye on. I am consistently on a tight rope to appropriately balanced those voices. But as with so many things where balance is key, keeping an eye on the middle or the long-distance can really help us get it right.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 03:23</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second question was one of cohesion and specifically cohesion over the competition. Brian asked how, if people feel disadvantaged, you can foster a feeling of cohesion rather than competition? And Matt's first answer was that competition is great. Specifically, he said that competition is great as long as you consider where your collaboration fits into the mission. And he also spent some time exploring how competitors in the ecosystem can still work from a community-first mindset. I personally cannot agree enough about some of the benefits of collaboration alongside your competitors. I remind sponsored contributors from time to time, and I think it's true for any contributor that you are an employee of your company first and a contributor to WordPress second. However, once you step into contribution time, your main concern is the users of WordPress, or new contributors, or the health of the WordPress ecosystem as a whole or the WordPress project. So you get all this subject matter expertise from competitive forces, collaborating in a very us versus the problem way. And when you do that, you're always going to find a great solution. It may not be as fast as you want it to build things out in the open in public. And so sometimes we get it wrong and have to come back and fix it but still, given time, we're going to come out with the best solution because we have so many skilled people working on this.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 05:01</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And then the third question that I wanted to really touch on is the question of those we leave behind. Brian asked Matt if he thought mid-sized agencies and mid-sized consultants were being squeezed out with the block editor. Matt's high-level answer was no, and I tend to agree with him. It's not all mid-sized anything any more than it's all small-sized anything. His answer continued to look at what stands to change for users with the block editor and who really can stand to benefit. It made me think back to my WordPress 5.0 listening tour. We launched WordPress 5.0, which was, in case anyone forgets, the first release with the block editor in it. I took a six-month-long tour to anywhere that WordPressers were so I could hear their main worries, what Brian is saying in there, and what Matt is saying to really came up all the time in those conversations. And basically, it was that this update takes all the power away from people who are building websites. And in these conversations, and Matt and Brian's conversation, it was really focused on our freelancers and consultants. But at the same time, all of them heard that this update gives power back to all of the people who could build websites.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 06:28</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I could not shake the feeling at the time. And honestly, I can't shake it now that no high-end consultants, or freelancers, or any other developer or site creator sit around just longing for maintenance work. After six months of talking to people, I didn't hear anyone say, "you know, I just love making the same author card over and over and over." Or, "updated the footer every week, this month. And that's why I got into this business." And more than the feeling that there just wasn't anyone who just loved maintenance, I got a feeling that there were real problems that needed to be solved for these clients and that they wanted to solve them. And that they also would gladly trade updating footers for the much more interesting work of creating modern and stylish business hubs based on WordPress for the clients who trust them so much. All of that, I guess, is to say that, yes, the block editor does give power back to our clients again, but not at the expense of those who have to build the sites in the first place. I think it stands to restore everyone's sense of agency more than we truly realize. So that's my deep dive on WordCamp Europe; I included links to the demo and the talk below, just in case you haven't seen them yet. And you want to get a little bit of insight into the full context of the conversations that I just did a bit of a deep dive into.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy 08:15</strong></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And now it's time for our smallest of big things. All right, I have three things for you today. Number one, tomorrow, we package WordPress 5.8 beta three. If you've never had a chance to stop by the core channel in slack for the past packaging process, I really encourage you to stop by; we call them release parties. It's a bunch of people who stand around and help get it done. So you can also see how it gets done. And if you're feeling brave, you can even try your hand at testing out one of the packages as soon as it's ready. The second thing is that a week from tomorrow, we reach our first release candidate milestone. So if you have meant to submit any bugs or patches or if you've been procrastinating on documentation, or dev notes, right now is the time so that we can have a chance to get everything into the release by the time we reach the release candidate milestone on the 29th. And the third thing is that we are currently right in the middle of WordCamp Japan. That is a great opportunity to meet some contributors and maybe even get started with contributions yourself. So stop by if you haven't had a chance to check it out already. I will leave a link in the show notes. And that, my friends, is your small list of big things. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress Briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in a couple of weeks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10837</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-06-21 12:33:22]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-06-21 12:33:22]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-19 17:25:49]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-19 17:25:49]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[episode-11-wordcamp-europe-2021-in-review]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/06/WP-Briefing-011.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10:14]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9.9MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/06/WP-Briefing-011.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_old_date]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2021-06-17]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[9891048]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 12: WordPress - In Person!]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/07/episode-12-wordpress-in-person/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10889</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy talks about WordPress - In Person! The WordPress events that provide the dark matter of connection that helps sustain the open source project.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Editor:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/"> Dustin Hartzler</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Logo:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/"> Beatriz Fialho</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Production:<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/mkaz/"> </a><a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons">The tragedy of the commons</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://wordpress.org/news/2021/06/wordpress-5-8-release-candidate/">WordPress 5.8 Release Candidate announcement </a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript </h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:11</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress Briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project, some insight into the community that supports it, and get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go!</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Today we're talking about one of my favorite parts of the project - WordPress events. The in-person component of the project is the dark matter that helps us build resilience and thrive as a group. A lot of what I'm going to share applies to every WordPress event, whether it's a meetup or workshop, a contributor day, any other sort of format. But I'll be focused on WordCamps. It's been a while since we had any in-person WordCamps. Our last two were WordCamp Malaga in Spain and WordCamp Greenville in the US. But that hasn't stopped anyone from gathering people together online. Which honestly makes a lot of sense for WordPress. Because there are many reasons we gather, the main three reasons are connecting, inspiring, and contributing. It's true. It says so right in our documentation, "paper rustling." All WordPress events should connect WordPress users, inspire people to do more with WordPress, and contribute to the WordPress project. As an aside, I'll tell you that some groups also get to collaborate and educate in there, but connect, inspire, contribute. Those are the big three. And that's what I'm talking about today. And if you subscribe to this podcast for the back office deep cuts, I'll also have a few of those for you. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>01:57</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Alright, so first up, connect. WordCamps are generally annual-ish gatherings organized by local WordPress meetup groups. They're not meant to be big or fancy. The definition of the minimum viable product for WordCamp is 50 people gathered all day to talk about WordPress. They are intentionally affordable to allow people from all walks of life to attend, meet, share and learn. This is made possible by donations and sponsorships from local businesses and larger businesses in the WordPress ecosystem. And this helps us get people connected to those in their community that works with or are sustained by WordPress. That connection feeds into the overall health of the global WordPress project. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>02:45</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Next up is inspire. WordCamps do not discriminate. They are open to any WordPress users, developers, designers, or other enthusiasts, regardless of their level of experience. And because of this, sessions generally span a variety of formats. So presentations or live demos to workshops or panels, any other format you can think of. But that also means that there are a variety of skill levels represented. There's always content about how to use WordPress. That’s a given. But you can also count on content that inspires people to do more with their own dreams and aspirations. When I was still organizing WordCamps, my favorite thing was seeing people who came back year after year, putting into practice something that they learned the year before. It is that <em>Choose Your Own Adventure</em> aspect to WordCamps that lets people see the edge of their ideas and then expand that just a little bit further. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>03:42</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And finally, contribute. WordCamps often have a contribution component to them. Sometimes it's just a talk telling you how you can get more involved in the WordPress project. But sometimes, it's a whole contributor day. And those range in size from single focus, like everyone, will show up and learn how to review a theme or a focus from every team that we have, like at the big flagship events where we gather hundreds of people into a room just to contribute to WordPress and all of the teams that go with it. Getting started with contributing can be daunting, but it is also essential to avoid something called the Tragedy of the Commons, an economic concept. So I'll share a link to that in the show notes below. But the most important thing, the most important thing to remember, is that WordPress is open source. And we asked people to help us keep this great tool running by giving back a little bit of their time if they have gotten any benefit from the WordPress project or CMS over the course of their careers.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>04:40</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So that's it. The three big things you can get from a WordCamp. I know that I can't wait to get back to them myself because while a lot of these things can still happen online and do, it's really hard to replace the dark matter of in-person connections for open source projects. And since we're talking dark matter anyway, let's dig into it a little.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>05:01</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>At the start of the section, I mentioned that WordCamps are local, locally organized, and people are encouraged to attend locally. But I am part of a group that ends up traveling to a lot of WordCamps. If you don't know about the unseen work of WordPress, this raises eyebrows. So here is some clarification around the back office work that some of these traveling WordCampers often do. When I listed these out, there were about 20 different tasks, 20 different jobs, which was, frankly, a bit overwhelming when I listed them that way. So I've grouped them into kind of two genres, each with a group of current versus future types of work. So my two big buckets, big picture stuff, and then community stewardship.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>05:50</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The big picture stuff, our first big genre here, when you're looking at current topics, current issues kind of information, when we're working on big picture stuff, you get the clarification of the mission or vision of WordPress, the sharing of open source methods or processes that we use in the WordPress project, and also sometimes those goal-setting conversations that you have to have both because we have a bunch of teams and team reps, that have a lot of really great ideas about what can be done in their teams to help WordPress succeed. But then also, because when you are working, when you're contributing to a single team in the project, it can sometimes be hard to know how your work relates to the overall goals and visions of WordPress. And so that's part of the work that gets done that I do there.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>06:43</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And when you're looking at future topics, future issues, the second part of this genre, that stuff like starting conversations or discussions around what the future holds for WordPress, and that's the project as well as the technology or hearing from people about big things coming up for them. And any content that can support it, anything that I can provide to support those big things. It's also a good time for me and others to identify trends based on what I see in presentations or what I hear from people at social functions. Really, it's just a huge opportunity for information gathering to make sure that I know what everyone else in the project is trying to do and if they understand what the project is trying to do.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>07:32</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And then the second big genre of things that happen in that dark matter kind of work at WordCamps is what I call community stewardship—so taking care of the community itself for the project itself. And a lot of that work is actually incident response kind of work. So conflict resolution, mediation often happens at in-person events, but also uncovering the shared foundations, the shared understanding for upcoming changes. So a lot of really, in the weeds kind of change management work. And for me, it's certainly doing my best as a cultural liaison when I do see that there has been some miscommunication or gathering context for the latest disagreement that people are having with me so that I can clarify anything that was misunderstood from what I said. And also a little bit of policy clarification, just explaining why we do things and the way we do them. So for community stewardship, that's kind of the current stuff that we look at. And that I do when I'm traveling for WordCamps. </p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>08:36</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And then for the future tasks that we do with community stewardship in the project, that stuff like training, and that's training team reps, community deputies, or new contributors like it's, it's not really one type of training, necessarily. But then also, all of the checking in with our organizers, team reps, volunteers, sponsors, everyone like that, to make sure that what we have in the project and what's happening in the project, the tools that we have, the experience that contributors have while they are working here, and WordPress is good, and is what they need. We've got a lot of tools to get things done in WordPress, and we can always make them better. And so checking in with people to kind of see how those processes are, how the tools are making sure that I have an idea of where our holes are and what needs to be patched, and how we can patch them in the long run. So that's all of the future planning kind of work and topic stuff, just you know, making sure that WordPress has what it needs to survive long into the future and long after I'm doing anything with it, and long after you're doing anything with it either.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>09:56</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So, lots and lots of unseen work being done at our in-person events. But folks who keep a keen eye on the online global work of WordPress will probably recognize that a lot of that work is also done routinely on make.wordpress.org and within the making WordPress Slack. There’s just, I don't know, there's just something different about receiving information from a human being with a face rather than an avatar with a photo. So I guess at the end of the day, that means the dark matter that keeps open source together is really an issue of communication. And you'll get no arguments for me there.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>10:44</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>That brings us now to our small list of big things. And there's really just one big thing. And that's WordPress 5.8. We are about two weeks away from this big release; the community has been working tirelessly on it. And it's shaping up to be one of the most tested releases that we've had in a long time. Myself, I'm grateful to see so much activity before the release. Since 5.8 and 5.9 releases represent such monumental shifts in our software, I'm incredibly grateful to see so much activity prior to the release, especially in the beta period. We've been testing everything for it feels like six or eight months, and we're really starting to see the positive benefits of that. And I think that we, the WordPress community, should be really proud of everything that we're going to ship in 2021. Okay, so that was less of a small list of big things and really like one big thing with a generous garnish of encouragement, but you deserve it. So thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in a couple of weeks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10889</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-07-05 12:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-05 12:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-19 17:25:44]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-19 17:25:44]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[episode-12-wordpress-in-person]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11929853]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/07/WP-Briefing-012.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[11MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[12:12]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/07/WP-Briefing-012.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 13: Cherishing WordPress Diversity]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/07/episode-13-cherishing-wordpress-diversity/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[cbringmann]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=10949</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy discusses the importance of Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion to the fabric of the WordPress project and how we can move from a place of welcoming it to cherishing it.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you'd like answered? You can submit them to <a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Editor: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/">Dustin Hartzler</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Logo: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/">Beatriz Fialho</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Production: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/community/handbook/meetup-organizer/event-formats/diversity-speaker-training-workshop/">Diverse Speaker Training Workshop</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://josepha.blog/2020/12/23/a-wordpress-dinner-party/">A WordPress Dinner Party</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://josepha.blog/2018/11/06/the-burden-of-proof/">The Burden of Proof</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://josepha.blog/2021/03/05/leading-at-any-level/">Leadership At Any Level</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://josepha.blog/2019/03/02/building-a-culture-of-safety/">Building a Culture of Safety</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://josepha.blog/2020/03/27/leadership-basics-ethics-in-communication/">Leadership Basics: Ethics in Communication</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><a href="https://wordpress.org/support/wordpress-version/version-5-6/">WordPress 5.6</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Bonus resource: <a href="https://allienimmons.com/how-to-be-a-wordpress-ally/">How to Be a WordPress Ally</a></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>00:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress Briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project, some insight into the community that supports it, and get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. And before we get started, I have to be honest with you all, this episode and the next one have made me feel really anxious. This one is about Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in open source, and especially in WordPress. And the next one is about accessibility in WordPress. And I feel like there's just so much to do, and we don't do enough, but we do what we can. And still, we will never be done with that work. And if you don't know what I mean by Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion, you can kind of think of it this way. Diversity is bringing in people with different viewpoints and lived experiences. Equity is making sure everyone has what they need to get a fair chance of success, which is different from equality. And Inclusion is making sure that the environment is built to not only tolerate diverse groups but to celebrate them as well. So remember this as you listen to what I have to say here. We are never where we want to be in either of those spaces. But that shouldn't stop us from looking at the things we have done to get us in the right direction. All right. Here we go.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>01:54</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I say a lot that we are a project that serves a majority collection of minority voices. WordPress is global in reach and open source in nature. And you would assume that what allows the software to be used by anyone would also enable it to be built by anyone. After all, your location doesn't matter, and who employs you also doesn't matter. And your relative social standing certainly shouldn't matter. As long as you can communicate with the others contributing to the project, there should be no obstacle to your participation. The mission of the WordPress project is to democratize publishing, right? It's to get the ability to have a website tap into passive income on your web presence. I mean, the job is to level the playing field for everyone. However, it's my experience that bringing in new voices takes a lot of proactive work on behalf of leaders and contributors. It's not enough to say, "Hey, I'm having a party," you also have to say, "I'm having a party, and I'd like you to be there." It's not enough to think people will make their own space at this table. You have to make sure that you have table settings for everyone. And even beyond the basics of directing people to you.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>03:12</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And on toward the next steps, you have to be honest about the fact that open source contribution requires a fair amount of privilege. By privilege, I mean the luxury of extra time or extra funding or just an understanding employer. WordPress supports 41% of the web. I think it's 42% of the web right now. But less than 1% of people who use WordPress show up to help maintain it. And that 1% that does show up skews toward people who already have a pretty high level of representation and technology. And so, when you look at who is building it versus who is using it, it doesn't always match. And since what we build so frequently reflects who we are, sometimes what we build doesn't match the needs of the people who are using what we have.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>04:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>So what has WordPress done to be proactive on the question of Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion? There are quite a few unseen things that have gone into this over the years and a few pretty visible things. This is a very long list. And it has a whole lot of just reference material. And so the show notes today will come in handy for people, and there will be just a laundry list of linked resources for everyone.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>04:39</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>But the first thing that WordPress has done is that we have accepted the burden of proof. I'm going to share a post about this in the show notes. That means we accept that it's not the job of underrepresented folks to figure out if they are welcome. It's up to us to make it clear that they are. So, there are three big little things that the community has done over the years. One is that many teams open their text-based meetings with an explanation of what is done in the meeting, who comes to the meetings, where to find help if you're lost in the meeting, and for teams that have a specific type of requests that comes into those channels that aren't handled in those channels. They also will share where people can go to get those requests taken care of. Many teams have also updated their team handbooks to have good beginner docs, limited use of inside jokes or jargon, and good first bugs. And also, there is a code of conduct in the community declaring that everyone is welcome and clarifies what to do if you see folks being unwelcoming.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>05:51</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>A second big thing that folks in the WordPress community have done is written down what was unwritten. Having things clearly documented unlocks institutional knowledge that you'd otherwise have to know someone to get. Clarity and process and the structure help anyone engage with your organization, not just the people who have extra time to figure things out. What that looks like in the WordPress project is that many teams have documented their workflows and their working spaces and just their general team norms. Many teams have also started defining what it means to be a team rep and holding open processes to choose those team reps. Many other community leaders and I have written down countless unspoken rules, guidelines, and philosophical underpinnings so that people don't have to guess what we're doing or why we're doing things, or where we want to do them.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>06:46</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And the more visible thing that the WordPress project has been doing is that we found ways to invite people in, and they're not failsafe; they’re not foolproof, but it is certainly a step in the right direction. The first one is an ongoing, diverse speaker training initiative. And I'll include a link to that in the show notes as well. It is run by Jill Binder and a fantastic group of contributors that collaborate with her. And I really have loved watching that particular program grow and flourish and help WordPress make a difference where we absolutely can.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>07:27</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing that was pretty visible about how we invited people in was at the end of 2020, and we had an all-women and nonbinary release squad for our biggest release of the year; WordPress 5.6. I had a group of probably 70 women and nonbinary identifying folx who joined in the process and joined in learning more about the process. Some of them have continued in the project. Others have stepped away for various reasons. But all of them are welcome to return. And I encourage everyone to return to contribution when time and resources make that possible for you.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>08:09</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And then the third thing that we've done, which I have talked about a lot, is the revival of the testing and triage practices. That has been work that's been ongoing for a number of years. And it happens across multiple teams. It is not always immediately clear to people why the testing work. And the triage work is identifiable for me as a way to invite people into this process. And so I'll be briefly clear about it right now. So testing as a practice brings in the users that otherwise don't have a lot of spare time and that extra privilege to like, figure out what's going on with WordPress, and contribute their own fixes to problems. They can give back to this project by being co-developers with us, co-creators with our entire process of making WordPress real and usable for the largest number of people that we can because we now support 42% of the web. And then, the triage practice invites in a diverse voice of people. Because you don't necessarily always need to know everything about a project to help with triage. And when you're helping with triage, you get active learning through participating in the process. But you also get passive learning from the people who already know huge amounts about the project and the process and everything that goes into it. And so it's a low key low stress way to get your feet wet and start building that knowledge that sometimes is hard to come by unless you are actively working in it. So the testing practices, the triage practices, I really to the core of my being believe that those are active and ongoing ways for us to invite people who otherwise wouldn't have a chance to get their voices heard in an open source project. And y'all, as I said at the start, y’all, there's nothing about this list that I just shared, which makes me feel like our work on this is done. Just like any muscle, you don't fight to peak fitness, and then hit the big stop button on time and say, "Now, I never have to work out again." If we did, the world would be a very different place probably. But it does then lead us to the next steps for fostering a community culture that's as broad as the people who use this software. If you believe in leadership at any level, as I do, there are a ton of things that you can do right now. But I'll boil them down into three big chunks of things.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>10:54</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>First, check your community area, or whatever community you want to apply this to, for things that need a little more proactive work. I will share a post called<em> Building A Culture of Safety</em> that will take you through a list of good first steps. And it is not as hard as it looks. When you say build a culture of safety, there are many really clear-cut minor changes that you can ask people to make and, in like, four or five different areas that can help your community be more welcoming and more open.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>11:30</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The second thing that you can do is know that small changes add up over time and commit to making those changes where you can. If you are elite at any level, you know that supporting people and processes is the responsibility of everyone in the group. And if you can make your own autonomous decisions and commit to making small changes that make a big difference over time, you will be part of that solution. And that is not specific to any one group that we have in our communities. You can be an ally for anyone, whether they look like you, whether they have your same experiences, or not. And sometimes, it's as easy as just holding space for the people who haven't had a chance to talk yet. And on the subject of holding space and the way that we communicate.&nbsp;</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>12:22</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>The third thing that I think is incredibly important is that you can take on as a foundational personal practice the concept of ethical communication. I'll share a post about that as well in the show notes, but the core of it is that you have to know that what you say and don't say what you do and don't do has an impact on others and embrace that responsibility. All right, so you made it all the way through, and I am so proud of you. I'm sure you have questions about this. And I encourage you to share those. You can email them to me at wp briefing@wordpress.org.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy&nbsp; </strong>13:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This brings us to our small list of big things. I've got two things for you today. First and foremost, WordPress 5.8 gets released tomorrow. It's a big release, and lots of people have been working on it. So get your update processes ready and keep an eye on wordpress.org/news for the announcement post. Second, and still pretty important, team reps have been working on their quarterly check-ins so that all other teams can get an idea of what's happening around the WordPress office. Keep an eye out for that post on make.wordpress.org/updates. And that is your smallest of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress Briefing. I'm your host Joseph Hayden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in a couple of weeks.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>10949</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-07-19 12:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-19 12:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-19 23:27:37]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-19 23:27:37]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[episode-13-cherishing-wordpress-diversity]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[13MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/07/WP-Briefing-013.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[14:21]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/07/WP-Briefing-013.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[10573955]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[13841598]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
					<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Episode 14: The Art and Science of Accessibility]]></title>
		<link>https://wordpress.org/news/2021/08/episode-14-the-art-and-science-of-accessibility/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[eidolonnight]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://wordpress.org/news/?post_type=podcast&#038;p=11096</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>In this episode, Josepha Haden Chomphosy discusses the nuances of building accessible software, the differences between access, usability, and accessibility, and how this all applies to the WordPress project.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><em><strong>Have a question you’d like answered? You can submit them to&nbsp;<a href="mailto:wpbriefing@wordpress.org">wpbriefing@wordpress.org</a>, either written or as a voice recording.</strong></em></p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Credits</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li>Editor:&nbsp;<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/dustinhartzler/">Dustin Hartzler</a></li><li>Logo:&nbsp;<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/beafialho/">Beatriz Fialho</a></li><li>Production:&nbsp;<a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/cbringmann/">Chloé Bringmann</a></li><li>Transcription: <a href="https://profiles.wordpress.org/eidolonnight/">Nicholas Garofalo</a></li><li>Song: Fearless First by Kevin MacLeod</li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>References</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:list -->
<ul><li><a href="https://wordpress.org/about/accessibility/">About WordPress Accessibility</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/accessibility/">Make WordPress Accessibility Team</a></li><li><a href="https://twitter.com/wpaccessibility">WordPress Accessibility Team Twitter</a></li><li><a href="https://make.wordpress.org/accessibility/handbook/best-practices/">WordPress Accessibility Handbook</a></li><li><a href="https://developer.wordpress.org/coding-standards/wordpress-coding-standards/accessibility/">Accessibility Coding Standards</a></li><li><a href="https://www.w3.org/WAI/intro/wcag">Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG)</a></li><li><a href="https://www.a11yproject.com/checklist/">A11y Checklist</a></li><li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_divide">The Digital Divide</a></li></ul>
<!-- /wp:list -->

<!-- wp:heading -->
<h2>Transcript</h2>
<!-- /wp:heading -->

<!-- wp:more -->
<!--more-->
<!-- /wp:more -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>[contemporary intro music]</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 0:10</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Hello, everyone, and welcome to the WordPress Briefing, the podcast where you can catch quick explanations of the ideas behind the WordPress open source project, some insight into the community that supports it, and get a small list of big things coming up in the next two weeks. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Here we go.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>[musical interlude]</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 0:28</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>This is the second of my big scary topics for this month. I'll be talking about accessibility, which much like Diversity, Equity and Inclusion, or DEI in the last episode, is one of those areas where the work is never finished. Also, like DEI in last episode, I feel strongly about accessibility and the need for accessible experiences in the world, but I'm aware that this is an area where I'm still learning.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 1:04</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>WordPress has both an accessibility statement and team, which makes a lot of sense given that the software supports so many different people, and industries, and cultures. But if you're not quite bought into the idea that software should be accessible, or that accessible software can't also be usable, then this is the episode for you.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 1:25</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Before I joined the WordPress project, the majority of my work with accessibility was in the context of the digital divide. Now, when talking about the digital divide, there are three concepts around quote-unquote, "getting things to people," and those are access, usability, and accessibility. Sometimes these words seem interchangeable, but ultimately they have nuanced differences that address different problems. And I like to think of them this way.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Access is making sure that someone can obtain something.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Usability is making sure that the user experience is understandable or coherent.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And accessibility is making sure that it's usable by the largest number of people.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I have always considered each as a subset of the one that came before it. So having something everyone can access is good, but easy to access and easy to use is better. Easy to use is good, but easy to use and easily accessible is better.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 2:27</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>After joining WordPress, I discovered that accessibility in the context of software building is well, substantially more complicated. There's no such thing as perfect accessibility, or a site that is 100% accessible, and many aspects are pretty open to interpretation. It turns out that accessibility, like so many things in WordPress, is a complicated intersection of art and science.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>As an example, there's a rule that says, "Ensure that links are recognizable as links." A fast shorthand to accomplish that, that we see all over the internet, is to underline all links or put that icon next to it that says, "This opens in a new tab." You know that icon that's a box with an arrow? That definitely has a name, that I definitely don't know? That icon. [laughing] But those solutions don't necessarily fit every context that you'll find a link in, and that's where we see that intersection between the art of communication and the science of necessity.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 3:32</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>If you came with me earlier on the idea that accessibility is a subset of usability, and it's not a far leap to say that the choices around accessibility implementations should always include design and the overall user experience.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I know that some of you are thinking, "But we have guidelines! Like, that's why we have the guidelines, so that not everything has to be a gray area." And on the one hand, yeah, that's true. There are a lot of guidelines. There are guidelines for the code, and what the code produces, and the design elements. But I worry that when a solution is driven solely by rules, rather than reasons, we run the risk of throwing out the good along with the bad.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 4:15</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Accessibility has been a consistent topic of debate in the project for as long as I can remember, and based on all of this, it's really clear why. There are a few big picture questions that still deserve some sort of canonical answer for WordPress, and where possible I dig in and research the positions that everyone has taken in the past. But I also have questions about how to move everything forward, especially as the editing experience gets more and more standardized across the software, which reduces cognitive load, shortens the learning curve, etc.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>What is the future possibility for having a series of more niche admin interface options?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>What would it be like to be able to account for functional limitations in a way that lets site builders select what is needed for their clients or organization, or just individual situations they know their sites would be maintained under?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>What more could we do if part of the setup flow of WordPress was to select some bundle of potential add ons for neuro diversity, or colorblindness, or dyslexia, and more?</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>It's a really big question I have.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 5:26</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And I have to be really transparent here and share that my foundational understanding of accessibility and usability is 10 plus years old, and I learned it in the context of people in education, not software. So a lot of my questions about the future of accessibility and WordPress is the result of old knowledge exploring new spaces, which means they are a little untested. And I'm so grateful for the contributors who point out what the current research and thinking is, in this incredibly complex field.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 6:00</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>I normally like to wrap up the briefing with a tidy takeaway, but this particular topic doesn't really lend itself to that. So I'll leave you with this. I really believe in WordPress' mission to democratize publishing. And I, for one, will never stop learning about what gives people more access to the software, and what makes the software more usable, and especially how we can combine usability with accessibility in a way that puts form and function on a level playing field.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>[musical interlude]</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 6:40</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And now, that brings us to our small list of big things.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>Thing one, it's that time of year where many of our community members take a short break to relax and refresh. I'll be taking a bit of a break during the month of August, and so the WP Briefing will return again starting in September.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And thing two, huge thanks to the production crew that helps me make this podcast every couple of weeks, but a special shout out to our editor Dustin Hartzler, who makes quick work of all of my rambling thoughts.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p><strong>Josepha Haden Chomphosy</strong> 7:09</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>And that is your small list of big things. Thank you for tuning in today for the WordPress Briefing. I'm your host, Josepha Haden Chomphosy, and I'll see you again in September.</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->

<!-- wp:paragraph -->
<p>[contemporary outro music]</p>
<!-- /wp:paragraph -->]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>11096</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2021-08-02 12:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2021-08-02 12:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2021-07-30 16:36:33]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2021-07-30 16:36:33]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[episode-14-the-art-and-science-of-accessibility]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[podcast]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
										<category domain="post_tag" nicename="wp-briefing"><![CDATA[wp-briefing]]></category>
						<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize_raw]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7554656]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wpas_done_all]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_last_editor_used_jetpack]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[block-editor]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_publicize_twitter_user]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[@WordPress]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[227158]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[episode_type]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[audio]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[audio_file]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/07/WP-Briefing-014.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[duration]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7:49]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[filesize]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[7.6MB]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[date_recorded]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[explicit]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[block]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							<wp:postmeta>
		<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[enclosure]]></wp:meta_key>
		<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[https://wordpress.org/news/files/2021/07/WP-Briefing-014.mp3]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
							</item>
				</channel>
</rss>
